<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/4/2014 10:28:33 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TITLE">
			<Text>The Philistines</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_STATBOX">
			<Text>[NEWLINE]        Leader: Abimelech[NEWLINE]        Unique Unit:Peleset[NEWLINE]        Unique Building: Brewery[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				The Philistines were people of Aegean origin who settled on the southern coast of Palestine in the 12th century bc, about the time of the arrival of the Israelites. According to biblical tradition, the Philistines came from Caphtor (possibly Crete). They are mentioned in Egyptian records as prst, one of the Sea Peoples that invaded Egypt in about 1190 bc after ravaging Anatolia, Cyprus, and Syria. After being repulsed by the Egyptians, they occupied the coastal plain of Palestine from Joppa (modern Tel Aviv–Yafo) southward to the Gaza Strip. The area contained the five cities (the Pentapolis) of the Philistine confederacy (Gaza, Ashkelon [Ascalon], Ashdod, Gath, and Ekron) and was known as Philistia, or the Land of the Philistines. It was from this designation that the whole of the country was later called Palestine by the Greeks.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Philistines expanded into neighbouring areas and soon came into conflict with the Israelites, a struggle represented by the Samson saga in the Old Testament. With their superior arms and military organization the Philistines were able (c. 1050) to occupy part of the Judaean hill country. They were finally defeated by the Israelite king David (10th century), and thereafter their history was that of individual cities rather than of a people. After the division of Judah and Israel (10th century), the Philistines regained their independence and often engaged in border battles with those kingdoms.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Aegean Origins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				The Philistines first appear in the Table of Nations in Genesis: "Mizraim (a son of Ham) begot Ludim, Anamim, Lehabim, Naphtuhim, Pathrusim, and Casluhim (from whom came the Philistines and Caphtorim)."1 Mizraim is the Hebrew word that is commonly translated as "Egypt," thus the Philistines are ethnically related to the Egyptians.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, note that the Casluhim are divided into the Philistines and Caphtorim (in fact, the Philistines are frequently identified with Caphtor, the Hebrew name for at least the island of Crete and perhaps for the whole Aegean region). This indicates that their origins lie in the area of Crete, western Asia Minor, and the Aegean Sea, and modern archeology bears this out. For instance, Philistine pottery resembles that of the Minoan and Mycenaean (Homeric Greek) civilizations to the point that a material connection is beyond question. Other substantial links to the area include early Greek weapons, armor, dress, burial methods, military tactics, government, religion, etc.
			</Text>
		</Row>

				<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_HEADING_3">
		<Text>Sea Peoples</Text>
	</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TEXT_3">
			<Text>
				Although the link is frail, most archaeologists suggest that the Peleset Sea Peoples that invaded Egypt are the Philistines, given the lingüistic link between both denominations, though some modern scholars suggest the Peleset were Persian rather than Philistine, making it an unresolved issue.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite their early dominance, the bulk of the Philistine people did not migrate to coastal Canaan for another nearly two and a half centuries. What caused the main body of Sea Peoples-as they are known to historians—to cross the Mediterranean is not entirely known. Perhaps the migration of Central European peoples into the Aegean region dislodged them, or maybe the early throes of Mycenaean decline played a part. Some have even suggested a terrible famine or a volcanic eruption as reasons for their relocation. Whatever the cause, the annals of the time record that the Sea Peoples were strong enough to overwhelm the Hittite Empire in Asia Minor, as well as other nations down the Mediterranean coast. Not content with these conquests, they set out to invade Egypt between the reigns of Pharaohs Merneptah (c. 1224-1216 bc) and Rameses III (c. 1174-1144 bc).
			</Text>
		</Row>

				<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_HEADING_4">
		<Text>The Pentapolis</Text>
	</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TEXT_4">
			<Text>
				One massive sea battle in the Nile Delta region during the reign of Rameses III put an end to the Sea Peoples' advance. Though normally outmatched on water, Pharaoh won a decisive victory, capturing large numbers of Sea Peoples. As new vassals of Egypt, they were placed in Egyptian fortified cities up the coast in southwestern Canaan where small Philistine colonies already existed, and many of them—particularly those of the Peleset tribe—settled permanently in the area. They formed a league of five major cities (a Pentapolis): Gaza,Ashkelon, Ashdod, Ekron, and Gath, each of which was ruled by a "lord" (Hebrew seranim, which is perhaps better rendered as "tyrant," a Greek concept).

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Now being the majority people in the area, it did not take the Philistines long to ignore Egyptian overrule (Egypt had been weakened and exhausted by its conflict with the Sea Peoples) and to carve out their own nation between the desert buffer of Sinai and the weak, disunited, hill-country Israelite tribes. Their rise to power began in the early- to mid-twelfth century BC (for instance, the Philistines conquered Ashkelon in about 1175 bc), contemporaneous with the end of Deborah's judgeship and the length of Gideon's. By the days of Jephthah, Samson, and Samuel in the early eleventh century, the Philistines dominated most of the land of Canaan from Sinai to Galilee, especially in the areas closer to the coast.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A key to their dominance lay in their more advanced material culture. While the Israelites and Canaanites of the highlands still practiced Bronze Age skills, the Philistines had advanced to an Iron Age culture, making them nearly invincible on the battlefield
			</Text>
		</Row>

				<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_HEADING_5">
		<Text>Philistine Culture</Text>
	</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TEXT_5">
			<Text>
				While a fair amount is known about the Philistines from textual sources, only recently have archeological finds begun to flesh out Philistine culture. For instance, relatively little is known about the original Philistine language except that, upon arriving in Canaan, it seems they quickly adopted the Semitic language of the area while retaining words from their original Indo-European tongue, including personal names. In November 2005, a small pottery shard bearing an inscription containing two names linguistically resembling "Goliath" was found in the ruins of Gath. There is no evidence that it refers to the biblical Goliath, but it confirms the general historicity of the story in I Samuel 17.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The artifacts being dug up from the ruins of Philistine cities reveal that Philistine culture was as advanced as their weaponry. Their art was refined, being heavily influenced by typically Mycenaean motifs with Egyptian and later Canaanite styles added to their repertoire. While its roof may not have been redundantly supported, their Temple of Dagon in Gaza—similar in design to Cretan architecture—supported about three thousand people on its roof, making it an imposing edifice. The evidence found in the tells of the Pentapolis bears out that, for the time, the Philistines built large, planned cities complete with fortresses, palaces, temples, and markets, all of which were surrounded by thirteen-feet-thick walls.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anciently, the Philistines were also renowned for both their production and consumption of alcoholic beverages. Numerous finds have exposed a well-managed spirits industry, from breweries and wineries to retail outlets that advertised beer, wine, and strong drink. Among the most numerous artifacts unearthed from Philistine ruins are beer mugs and wine craters (large drinking bowls). The story of Samson's wedding feast alludes to the Philistine practice of engaging in weeklong drinking parties, as the Hebrew word misteh, translated as "feast" in Judges 14:10, indicates a "drinking feast."

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the Old Testament, we find that the principal deity of the Philistines was Dagon. This deity, either a god of fish or of grain (the root dg can represent either idea, depending on the vowel used), was worshipped at least in the temples of Gaza, Ashdod, and Beth-shan. II Kings 1:1-6 records that at Ekron the god Baal-Zebub was venerated. There is thought to be some connection between these gods and similar ones worshipped by the Hittites, also a Hamitic people, who lived in Anatolia (Asia Minor). Over time, however, the Philistine deities began to resemble their Canaanite counterparts, though the Philistines retained a distinctive worship ritual.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Judges 16:23-24 contains snatches of a song sung in the Temple of Dagon at Gaza celebrating the successful capture of Samson. Cultic artifacts found at Ashdod suggest music played a prominent role in Philistine worship, both singing and instrumental music, particularly the use of the lyre. This same passage also shows a Philistine penchant for performance art and entertainment (verse 25), another interest attributed to the Greeks.
			</Text>
		</Row>

				<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_HEADING_6">
		<Text>Legacy</Text>
	</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_LEUGI_PHILISTINE_TEXT_6">
			<Text>
				Unlike the common belief, the Philistines were not unsophisticated, uncultured brutes, but advanced, refined people. In fact, for several generations their culture was years ahead of Israel's, a disparity they maintained through their martial superiority. Nevertheless, their cosmopolitan sophistication could not hide their underlying rivalry against the Israelites and their God; they were a foreign people in the land God had promised to Abraham's descendants. Eventually the Israelites under David overcame the Philistine's might and advanced culture, making Israel the dominant force in the region.

				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE](Most of the contents of this civilopedia were written by Richard T. Ritenbaugh)
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Leader -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH">
			<Text>Abimelech</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_LIVED">
			<Text>c. 1000 BC</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_NAME">
			<Text>Achish - Suwardata (from an Egyptian record)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of the Philistines</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TITLES_1">
			<Text>King of Gath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Abimelech, also known as Achish, son of Maoch, was the king of Gath; one of the five cities in the Philistine Pentapolis. A contemporary of Kings Saul and David of Israel, biblical accounts place Abimelech as the king who ultimately defeated Saul's army at the battle of Gilboa, allowing the Philistines to gain control of several key cities in southern Canaan. Etymologically, Achish may also be related to Suwardata, a powerful regional king mentioned in the Amarna letters.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Kings of Gath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Not counting the potential inaccuracy of biblical accounts, it is difficult to fully reconstruct Abimelech's reign due to confusion surrounding the Philistine kings in general. It is possible that both Abimelech ("My Father is King") and Achish ("Gift of the Sun God") may have been royal titles instead of proper names. As a result, there are several different kings referred to as Abimelech or Achish, many of which were no doubt conflated in historical accounts.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Achish, in particular, appears in royal inscriptions uncovered at Ekron and contemporaneous Assyrian texts. This appears to indicate that either the name Achish was a common name for Philistine kings, used both at Gath and Ekron, or that the biblical editors adopted a known name of a Philistine king into narratives relating to earlier periods.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]An etymological link can also be found with the Canaanite King Suwardata mentioned in the Amarna letters. Suwardata is potentially an Indo-European cognate with the Hurrian Akishimige, the long form of Achish. If Suwardata is the same king as Achish, the Amarna letters indicate him being a powerful regional ruler sometime between 1350-1335 BC.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_HEADING_3">
			<Text>David</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Abimelech is primarily known through his interactions with David within the Book of Samuel. He is first mentioned when David seeks refuge from Saul in Gath. However, David is suspicious of the Philistine court and feigns madness in order to flee to Adullam. Later on, David once again flees from Saul, this time fearing for his life. Abimelech welcomes David and his 600 men to settle in Gath, and even assigns David to govern the city of Ziklag. Biblical accounts depict David as fooling Abimelech; as David raids the surrounding Canannite tribes he instead reports to Abimelech that he has been raiding Judah. By doing so, David quickly ingratiates himself into Abimelech's trust while still remaining faithful to Israel. The veracity of this tale is uncertain, but it seems unlikely that Abimelech would have been completely unaware of his vassal's activities. Additionally, prior to the battle of Gilboa, Abimelech repeatedly stresses David's fidelity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Battle of Gilboa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The most significant event of Abimelech's reign was his victory over Saul at the Battle of Gilboa. Gilboa was the name given to a low mountain range in central Israel, near Jezreel and the valley of Esdraelon. Abimelech gathered the Philistine rulers and marched with their units of hundreds and thousands against the army of Israel camped in Jezreel. Despite Abimelech's trust in David, David is said not to have participated in the battle on the insistence of the Philistine rulers; however, this detail also serves as a literary device to keep the figure of David as consistently loyal to Israel.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Philistine army is portrayed as formidable, routing the Israelite forces and slaying Saul's sons; Jonathan, Abinadab, and Melchishua. Saul himself is said to have either fallen on his own sword or asked a passing Amalekite to kill him in order to escape abuse and dishonor. Upon discovering the body of the Israelite king, the Philistines displayed Saul's armor in the temple of Ashtoreth (Astarte/Ishtar) and fastened the body to the city walls.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Abimelech's victory allowed the Philistines to capture and occupy several key cities in southern Canaan, expanding Philistine territory and influence. It also opened the path, whether deliberately or not, for David's ascension to the throne of Judah.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Verdict of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Like many Philistine historical figures, it is difficult to form an accurate judgment of Abimelech whose deeds are primarily known through biblical accounts. A primary text of their rivals, the Israelites, many passages of the Bible are primarily concerned with presenting the Philistines in contrast to Israel and attributing historical events to the faith (or lack thereof) of the Israelite and Philistine kingdoms. In this regard, Abimelech's victory at Gilboa is portrayed more the result of Saul loosing God's favor than due to any skill or leadership on Abimelech's part. Stripping hagiographical elements, it is possible to interpret the events of Samuel as Abimelech entering into an alliance with David to better the Philistine position in the ancient Levant. Abimelech's victory over Saul's army not only secured Philistine holdings in southern Canaan but also established a more favorable ruler in a neighboring rival kingdom.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Factoid</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ABIMELECH_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Abimelech is the subject of a popular modern Israeli riddle; "In my house it's so unpleasant, all full of crazy men." A rhyming couplet in the original Hebrew, the riddle is a reference to David feigning madness when first visiting Abimelech's court.</Text>
		</Row>


		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Salutations, weak and fragile friend. Come, join us in our festivities to our gods!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>I'm Achish, my people call me Abimelech, but some foreigners know me as Suwardata. Welcome to Philistia, have you brought something for the holy feast?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>We have guests it seems... Hopefully you'll not be here too long, for we are about to hold a week-long feast. Call me Abimelech, leader of the Philistines</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Your treachery shall not be forgotten. May our lands and gods be in war forever!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>At least my people enjoyed their faith, yours are cursed with your faith</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Dagon will surely favour you should you grant him this offering!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>Let us share! Let us feast!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>Maybe we could walk within our lands freely, and enjoy the graces of them both. And, their luxuries</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABIMELECH_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I see you are getting too near to Philistia. Know that we have all needed to defeat you and your frail gods, so you better stop</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Unit -->
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PHILISTINE_PELESET_TEXT">
			<Text>
				The Peleset were one of the nine sea peoples. Mentioned in various ancient Egyptian records, the Peleset inhabited what is today the Gaza Strip, parts of southern Israel and the northern Sinai. Many modern scholars believe that the Peleset came from Mycenae or Asia Minor, pointing at Philistine vases that have heavy Greek influences. Other scholars believe that the Peleset were not immigrants, but rather descended from Canaanites
			</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Building -->

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PHILISTINE_BREWERY_TEXT">
			<Text>
				The people of Philistia were famous all over the Levant and beyond for their high rate of alcohol consumption. Archaeologists have uncovered numerous beer mugs and wine craters, suggesting a culture known for their spirits’ industry. Philistine breweries and wineries publicized their collections of beer, wine and strong drink. The Philistines were notorious for their drinking parties, which purportedly lasted for an entire week, a practice of theirs referred to in the Bible.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>