<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: VANILLA Vanilla -->
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Ahem. I am Ludwig II, King of Bavaria. I assure you, you sleep not. You have stumbled upon a dream, yes - no, a fantasy; a paradise unrivalled on all the earth - but it is a fantasy of mine into which you step. My dream in which I hope you'll stay a while.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>You made it. I am Ludwig II, King of Bavaria. Take in, for a moment, the fresh, alpine air, and if you will, listen to the silence around us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I shall now retreat to one of my great sanctums for good.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--First Greeting from leaders that don't have their own file yet-->
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH">
			<Text>...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_TRADE_1">
			<Text>Didn't I already say you would have to do better?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_TRADE_2">
			<Text>I already told you to only bother offering a fair deal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_TRADE_3">
			<Text>Are you offering deals you know I won't accept?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_REPEAT_1">
			<Text>Back so soon?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_REPEAT_2">
			<Text>You must be obsessed with me. Why else would you keep coming back?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_1">
			<Text>I don't share those feelings you must have for me, so don't bother coming back.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_2">
			<Text>It's not flattering that you would keep stalking me like this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>I like talking to you. It's good to see you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_2">
			<Text>It's always a pleasure speaking with you. What would you like to discuss?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_3">
			<Text>Hello again my friend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_4">
			<Text>Great to see you again. Do you come with news, or perhaps an offer?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Greetings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_3">
			<Text>What would you like to discuss?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_4">
			<Text>What brings you here today?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_5">
			<Text>Go on. I have some time for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_6">
			<Text>Let us begin.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>What do you want?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_2">
			<Text>Why are you here?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_3">
			<Text>What business do you have here?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_4">
			<Text>Oh great, you again?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_5">
			<Text>Get on with it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_DESTRUCTION_LOOMS_1">
			<Text>The end is near. What is it you wish to speak about?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_DESTRUCTION_LOOMS_2">
			<Text>I know when I'm staring defeat in the face. Have you come to discuss terms?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Is it not time we ended this war? It has been quite bad for my skin.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_2">
			<Text>For the good of our two nations, let us make peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_3">
			<Text>The time has come to put down our arms.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Come to beg for mercy?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Lost the will to fight?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>What's the matter? Tired of battle?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_BROKEN_MILITARY_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>What business does a dishonorable individual such as yourself have here?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_WORKING_WITH_1">
			<Text>Always a pleasure working with you, friend. What brings you to my court?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_COOP_WAR_1">
			<Text>It won't be long before we'll have dealt with {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey}. I can just feel it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_COOP_WAR_2">
			<Text>I hope you're looking forward to the downfall of {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey} as much as I am.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_COOP_WAR_3">
			<Text>Soon we'll have dealt with {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey} once and for all.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I heard from my ministers that you were at war. I think it's very cute that they call what you've gotten yourself into a war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I hope your war ends soon. I would hate to never see your pretty face again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Soldiers marching upon my borders. How dare you? Get rid of them at once!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>The positioning of your military is somewhat worrisome. I advise you to withdraw for the sake of future peace. Now, what would you like to talk about?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>You keep settling over the land, leaving nothing for me and my people. Do not awaken me from this dream of mine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>You've started to settle upon lands that would look better as mine. I want to warn you against that. Do not come between me and my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>Stop what you're doing! That land is better to belong to me and my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>You've started to buy up territory that would look better as mine. I want to warn you against that. Do not come between me and my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Welcome back. Since you were last here, I've heard you've gotten yourself quite a powerful military.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>I've heard of your great wealth, and I've been looking for someone to join me in my next project. You understand what I'm saying?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES">
			<Text>My dear, if the size of your empire is anything to go by...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY">
			<Text>I feel much safer knowing how small your army is.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER">
			<Text>I know what you are, barbarian. I won't have you destroy this beautiful land.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_1">
			<Text>No, sorry. I couldn't stand the thought of it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOF_AI_DENOUNCE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Friend, I have a serious matter to discuss. My relationship with {1_CivName} has broken down, and I need you to denounce them as a show of support. What do you say?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOF_NOT_HONORED_1">
			<Text>Pathetic. So you now show your true colors. The world will know of your dishonor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOF_NOT_HONORED_2">
			<Text>So that is the kind of ally you are then? The rest of the world's leaders will hear of your betrayal.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DENOUNCING_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I've had enough of you. I've told the other leaders of the world that working with you is a mistake.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DENOUNCING_FRIEND_2">
			<Text>Alright, enough is enough. Informing everyone else of your ill deeds is long overdue.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>What is wrong with you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_2">
			<Text>This really upsets me, you know?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DOFED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Ahhh, I've noticed that you've become friends with {1_CivName}. Glad to hear of it. I'm already on good terms with them myself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DOFED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>I recommend that you not get too close with {1_CivName}. If so... we might have problems getting along.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I'll have you know that {1_CivName} and I have worked together in the past, and I have the utmost respect for them. Just so you're aware.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>Glad to hear there are others in the world which share my disgust with {1_CivName}. They are clearly not to be trusted.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Being on such good terms, I couldn't help but notice that you'd become friends with {1_CivName}. I have done the same. Perhaps this makeshift alliance will lead to great things in the future?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I share your convictions that {1_CivName} only causes problems for the civilized empires of the world. Perhaps the combination of our denouncements will teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Oh great, now the vermin are breeding. Now I have to deal with both you and {1_CivName}? I'll have to teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Anyone who you don't get along with is clearly worth building a friendship with. Give {1_CivName} my regards.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Ludwig Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I hope you're not planning an attack. But I wouldn't be surprised. You always ruin everything beautiful.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Please don't say you're preparing to attack my territory. Why can't we just get along?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_KILLED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>It seems your word is worth nothing, as your conquest of {@1_MinorCivName} shows. How despicable. The world will know of your crimes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>Your wanton aggression against {@1_MinorCivName} does not go unnoticed. You will face serious consequences should you continue assault.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I'm seriously considering not inviting you to my next primere if you keep expanding into my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EXPANSION_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Could you think about - I don't know - maybe not expanding into lands that belong to me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EXPANSION_BROKEN_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>You told me that you would honour the boundaries of my empire. Why would you lie to a face like mine?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PLOT_BUYING_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I really wish you would stop buying all the land around my empire. It's putting my ministers into a panic.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PLOT_BUYING_WARNING_1">
			<Text>You recently purchased some land that I was planning to make the home of my next master project. Please be a bit more considerate next time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PLOT_BUYING_BROKEN_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>So you lied to me when you told me you would stop buying lands ripe for my castles? No birthday cards for you then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WORK_WITH_US_1">
			<Text>What do you say to a 'special' relationship with me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WORK_WITH_US_2">
			<Text>I thought we could stand to get a bit cosy, don't you think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>What do you say to a 'special' relationship with me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_2">
			<Text>I thought we could stand to get a bit cosy, don't you think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Oh just piss off.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DENOUNCE_2">
			<Text>You're a complete and utter bore, and I want the world to know about it.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DENOUNCE_3">
			<Text>I think the rest of the world deserves to know how deplorable you are as an ally and how unsatisfying you are as a lover.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>My disagreements with {1_PlayerName:textkey} have become too much to bear. This is a situation that can only be resolved on the battlefield. Will you join me, friend?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_2">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} has become a nuisance. One that can only be dealt with through war. I seek allies - can I count you among them?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_3">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} is a threat to the stability of this world. The time has come to deal with them once and for all. Will you assist me in this effort?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COOP_WAR_TIME_1">
			<Text>The time for war against {1_PlayerName:textkey} has come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_NOW_UNFORGIVABLE_1">
			<Text>Your actions are unforgivable. There can never be reconciliation between our two nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_NOW_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>Given the circumstances, I have no choice but to assume you are my enemy. As such, I will do what I must to protect my interests.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COMPLIMENT_1">
			<Text>I wanted to make it known to you that I value our friendship, and hope that it might remain strong.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_BOOT_KISSING_1">
			<Text>There is no greater and handsomer ruler as yourself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>I've no time for brutes like you that cannot appreciate beauty, so don't bother coming to me for anything in the future.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_MINOR_CIV_COMPETITION_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that you're getting a little friendly with {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. In case you weren't aware, they're within my sphere of influence, and I'd prefer if you stayed out of it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_MINOR_CIV_COMPETITION_2">
			<Text>I've noticed your relationship with {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. While that's nice, it would be best that you leave their protection to us. I'd hate for either of us to step on any toes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_1">
			<Text>It's pathetic that you would even think you have a chance with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_2">
			<Text>You're the worst. You know that? Just the worst kind of the worst.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_3">
			<Text>I'm really getting tired of seeing your face. It's so ugly and has such bad skin. And what is with that hair?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>If your army is any judge of character, then you must be quite spineless.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_MILITARY_2">
			<Text>With an army so weak it's a surprise your empire hasn't succumb to a barbarian invasion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_NUKE_1">
			<Text>Our words are backed with nuclear weapons!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_BULLY_1">
			<Text>It's a shame there are some leaders in this world who have their fun by picking on the weak. Don't you agree?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_1">
			<Text>Your people are so unhappy, suicide rates must be through the roof in your empire!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_2">
			<Text>Your people wouldn't be so unhappy if you would only let them come to Bavaria now and then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_CITIES_1">
			<Text>No wonder your people are miserable; crammed into such a small empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_POPULATION_1">
			<Text>Travelers have told us that your empire's economy is in pretty sad shape. If you beg a little I might give you a hand. Okay, actually I won't.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>Don't feel bad about your culture. You couldn't possibly compete with the culture of Bavaria.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_CULTURE_2">
			<Text>Your culture is so underwhelming. Try promoting some art now and again. Or build a castle. They're simply gorgeous. That's if you know how.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is asking the AI for something-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_NO_1">
			<Text>We've been over this before. The answer is still no.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Only because I like you so much.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DONT_SETTLE_YES_2">
			<Text>That land wasn't going to make for a good vista, so you may as well have it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Um, how about you not settle land that I want first, huh?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DONT_SETTLE_NO_2">
			<Text>I'll think about it. Hmmmm... no.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WORK_WITH_US_YES_1">
			<Text>Alright, yes. I think we could get a bit closer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WORK_WITH_US_YES_2">
			<Text>Great. How shall we celebrate?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DECLINE_1">
			<Text>No. You're just not my type.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DECLINE_2">
			<Text>Sorry, but I just don't want to be seen in such a relationship with you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COOP_WAR_YES_1">
			<Text>That sounds like a wise move. Let us take to the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_COOP_WAR_SOON_1">
			<Text>That is an intriguing offer. I accept. However, my empire is not yet prepared, so give me 10 turns. I will come to you again when I am ready.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_1">
			<Text>Very well. I do what I must to maintain peace in my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_2">
			<Text>I will do what it takes to keep the peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_3">
			<Text>Fine. But know that you poison your reputation with acts such as these. For what that might be worth to you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_1">
			<Text>Please. You're in no position to make such demands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_2">
			<Text>You should be well aware of your own inability to back those threats up.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_3">
			<Text>You're not fooling anyone. I have nothing to fear from you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_4">
			<Text>Haha! You are not strong enough to make such demands of me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You dare insult me in such a manner? If you want something so badly then do your best to come and take it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>You'll have to take it from my dead body.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>If you want that you'll have to come and get it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_4">
			<Text>Unacceptable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_5">
			<Text>Don't be a fool.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>You ask for too much. I will not drive my nation into poverty to satisfy your greed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_2">
			<Text>No. I have my dignity, and refuse to hand over such a great bounty so freely.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_3">
			<Text>Your desire to strip my lands of so much wealth is intolerable. Do not ask for so much.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_1">
			<Text>You threaten me again so soon? I refuse your demands, you vile beast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_2">
			<Text>Asking again so soon? You know that greed is a vice, great leader...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_3">
			<Text>Asking for the fruits of others' labor yet again? Your greed is legendary. I will not give in to you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_LETS_HEAR_IT_1">
			<Text>Let's hear your offer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_LETS_HEAR_IT_2">
			<Text>What do you propose?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PEACE_OFFER_1">
			<Text>The time has come to end this war. What do you think of this arrangement?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PEACE_OFFER_2">
			<Text>There is no point in this conflict continuing any further. Let us return to peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PEACE_OFFER_3">
			<Text>We must not let war define who we are. The time has come to make peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DEMAND_1">
			<Text>You have something I want. If you don't hand it over quietly I'll have no choice but to take it by force.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REQUEST_ITEM_1">
			<Text>Unfortunately I spent a little too much on my last project. Could you lend a friend a hand? I'm sure we can work out some kind of arrangement...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>What are you waiting for? Come, Bavaria awaits your gaze. Let beauty be not constrained by political borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_OPEN_BORDERS_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I would like your people to come visit Bavaria some time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PLAN_RESEARCH_AGREEMENT_1">
			<Text>I would like to lay plans for establishing a Research Agreement with your great nation. Doing so would require each of us to spend 150 [ICON_GOLD]. What do you think?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE](Agreeing will not form a Research Agreement yet)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESEARCH_AGREEMENT_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I feel that a Research Agreement is a mutually beneficial arrangement that would help serve to cement our Friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RENEW_DEAL_1">
			<Text>This deal strengthened our nations and our bonds of friendship. Shall we renew this deal and continue our shared prosperity?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WANT_MORE_RENEW_DEAL_1">
			<Text>This deal has faded in our eyes over the years. To renew this deal, we would need more from your side of the negotiation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>You have a resource that would look good in one of my castles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Attacked by another player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You seek only to destroy my beauty, but my beauty is immortalised in brick and stone.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>You wretch. Why must you distract me from my work?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>I may fail to overcome your evil, but it won't be for lack of effort.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Given the circumstances, destroying you would make victory all the sweeter.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>Destroy me if you can. I can promise you though, I will not fall before you easily.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_4">
			<Text>So be it. My armies will fight to the death against your wicked forces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_5">
			<Text>You will forever be known as a villain who preys on the weak.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_STRONG_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Do you really think that you can defeat me? Fool. Very well. Let us play this game then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_STRONG_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Your armies are welcome to come and enjoy the destruction that will befall them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_STRONG_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>Attacking me was a mistake. I will soon show you why.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>This will be a tale to tell.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_EXCITED_2">
			<Text>I've already begun drawing up plans to use your lands as the site of my next master project.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_EXCITED_3">
			<Text>This should be fun. I revel in every opportunity to defeat someone like you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_WEAK_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Even if this isn't the best time, it'll be one to write home about.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_STRONG_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Haha. Well, I won't question your decision, but it appears to me that you've made a big mistake.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>This is awkward. I liked you, and I am broken by this action.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>I would not be sad to see my office taken, if only I could guarantee the security of my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_MILITARY_PROMISE_BROKEN_1">
			<Text>You have betrayed your word. Make no mistake, the world will know of your treachery.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Declaring War-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_1">
			<Text>Glorious ballads will be sung about the legendary battles to come. Let us go to war, then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_2">
			<Text>I had a feeling that the two of us would some day meet in the field of battle. We will now see which of us is meant to be victorious.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>So many castle-less hills upon your landscape, it is too much to bare!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_LAND_2">
			<Text>You are too close for comfort. I need room to let my imagination run free.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>When I sleep, I dream, and whence all the world is mine, I may dream forever.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_2">
			<Text>I cannot let this world continue to be dominated by the ugly and mundane. I must bring beauty to this planet, and I begin by taking your lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>I've been waiting for this day to come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_2">
			<Text>I have waited long enough. I have seen an opening in your defense and I will use it to my advantage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_3">
			<Text>I have been waiting a long time for this day. Now would be a good time to put your affairs in order.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_4">
			<Text>It is now my time. I will defeat you and come one step closer to victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_5">
			<Text>Fate is not on your side. Crossing my path with such weakness is a mistake you will not long regret.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_6">
			<Text>The current situation cannot be ignored. It is now or never.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_7">
			<Text>I cannot ignore this chance to eliminate a potential competitor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_8">
			<Text>Your weakness presents to me a great opportunity. You have my apologies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>One last effort, alright? Once last dance upon the fields of battle, before all the world is vomited from my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_2">
			<Text>It is clear that you are strong. I will, however, find a way to defeat you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_3">
			<Text>You are a villain without equal. Within every fiber of my being, I know I must destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_4">
			<Text>Your might is unmatched, but I will find a way to defeat you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_5">
			<Text>The time to make a stand is now. The odds are not with me, but I find a way to destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_6">
			<Text>Your incredible strength will not deter me from finding a way to defeat you. May the fates smile on me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_7">
			<Text>Although I do not wish it, I fear that now may be my only opportunity to defeat you. Let us meet on the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_8">
			<Text>Destruction might be the fate which awaits me, but should I back down only eventual defeat awaits anyways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>Although feigning friendship with you wasn't very polite, few who make their mark on history were known for their manners. May your passage be swift.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_BETRAYAL_2">
			<Text>Your weakness is my opportunity. Placing any trust in me was a mistake.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_BETRAYAL_3">
			<Text>Regretfully, I must inform you of this betrayal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_BETRAYAL_4">
			<Text>I have to admit, I never really liked you much. Pretending to do so was getting old anyways. But enough with the small talk, it's time for you to die.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_WEAK_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>The odds are clearly not with me, but I see no alternative to revealing my deceptive practices. I can now only pray that my armies succeed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WAR_DEMAND_REFUSED_1">
			<Text>So be it. My armies will extract it from your lands then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WAR_DEMAND_REFUSED_2">
			<Text>Then war it is.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_1">
			<Text>What is your offer?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_2">
			<Text>What would you suggest?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_3">
			<Text>What is the price of peace?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>There can be no peace. Perhaps another day.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_NO_PEACE_2">
			<Text>This is not the time for negotiation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_NO_PEACE_3">
			<Text>We still have business to settle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>You're joking, right?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_1">
			<Text>Excellent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_2">
			<Text>Wonderful.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_3">
			<Text>I am pleased to hear this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_4">
			<Text>That is good to hear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_1">
			<Text>You have my thanks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_2">
			<Text>You are truly a great leader.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_3">
			<Text>History will long remember your great deeds.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_1">
			<Text>That is a shame.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_2">
			<Text>Perhaps another time then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_3">
			<Text>That is disappointing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SO_BE_IT_1">
			<Text>So be it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SO_BE_IT_2">
			<Text>Then you will be responsible for the consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SO_BE_IT_3">
			<Text>You will regret this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_1">
			<Text>For freeing those captives, you have my thanks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_2">
			<Text>I am appreciative for the actions you have taken on behalf of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_3">
			<Text>Thank you. May this be remembered as a historic event which brought our two great empires closer together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CULTURE_BOMBED_1">
			<Text>How dare you? Know that there will be consequences for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CULTURE_BOMBED_2">
			<Text>If you are trying to provoke a war, you're doing a fine job.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_BAD_1">
			<Text>Well, at least you're honest. But that may be your only good trait.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>A likely story.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_BAD_1">
			<Text>That is what I was afraid of.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I only hope that is indeed the case.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>We'll see about that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Yes, that's right.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>I remain confident that my decision was the best for my people and my nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_1">
			<Text>It seems that you cannot be reasoned with. What a shame.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_2">
			<Text>I have no more business with the likes of you then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_3">
			<Text>You disappoint us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_4">
			<Text>You know that this can only sow tension between our two nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: BWN Vanilla -->
		<!-- Statements to player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>I thought you might like to know that I've launched an invasion of one of your little pet states. The lands of {@1_MinorCivName} will make a fine addition to my own.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>Oops, it seems I've attacked your little friend {@1_MinorCivName}. Care to do something about it?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that I may have attacked {@1_MinorCivName}, a city-state under your protection. While it was not my goal to be at odds with your empire, this was deemed a necessary course of action.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>I've been informed that my empire has commenced an attack on {@1_MinorCivName}. I assure you, this was not on purpose, and hope that this does not serve to drive us apart.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EMBASSY_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>We should consider exchanging embassies, which would allow for more advanced diplomacy between our peoples.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EMBASSY_OFFER_1">
			<Text>We would like to set up an embassy in your capital. What do you think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_BULLIED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>Your bullying of {@1_MinorCivName} is intolerable. I demand that you refrain from squeezing tribute out of city-states under my protection.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_BULLIED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_2">
			<Text>I heard about what you did to {@1_MinorCivName}.  Did you not realize they are under my protection?  Do not provoke me further.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>We asked {@1_MinorCivName} for a tribute recently and they gave in. You promised to protect them from such things, but we both know you cannot back that up.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>Your little friend {@1_MinorCivName} is so easy to push around. They gave in to our tribute demands, and I don't believe you are in a position to do anything about it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that I may have bullied {@1_MinorCivName}, which is under your protection. You do not put their needs above mine, I hope.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>I've been informed that my armies have taken tribute from {@1_MinorCivName}, a city-state under your protection. I assure you, this was quite unintentional, and I hope that this does not serve to drive us apart.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SAME_POLICIES_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>Warm salutations to you wise leader! I'm pleased to see you also have chosen to follow the path of Freedom. The free world will be stronger with one more nation to help us all fight against oppression!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SAME_POLICIES_ORDER_1">
			<Text>Greetings comrade! I'm pleased to see you also have chosen to follow the path of Order. Perhaps we can find some opportunities to aid each other during our empires' next 5-Year Plans!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SAME_POLICIES_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>Welcome great emperor! I'm pleased to see you have also chosen to follow the path of Autocracy. May we work together to ensure that only the very strongest nations survive to achieve true greatness!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>How did one of your filthy agents somehow steal one of our basic technological secrets? These may be the last words we speak in peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_FRIENDLY_1">
			<Text>I am willing to overlook your recent theft of one of my technological secrets with a solemn promise that it won't happen again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you agreed to stop this petty thieving.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_BAD_1">
			<Text>Your indiscretion is not a surprise.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_STOP_SPYING_YES_1">
			<Text>As you request, our agents will not conduct operations in your territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_STOP_SPYING_NO_1">
			<Text>Our agents help keep our civilization safe from all threats, including you. They operate as we need them to, not as you ask.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_WARNED_ABOUT_INTRIGUE_1">
			<Text>Thank you for bringing this {@1_CivAdjective} plot to our attention. With this warning, we will be ready for whatever they may try. Your generous aid will be remembered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_DECEPTION_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is plotting against you. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_ARMY_SNEAK_ATTACK_KNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is currently marching an army to sneak attack your city of {2_CityName}. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_ARMY_SNEAK_ATTACK_UNKNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is currently marching an army your way in a sneak attack. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_AMPHIBIOUS_SNEAK_ATTACK_KNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} embarked an army with naval escorts to sneak attack your city of {2_CityName}. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_AMPHIBIOUS_SNEAK_ATTACK_UNKNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} embarked an army with naval escorts in a sneak attack against your civilization. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_KILLED_YOUR_SPY_1">
			<Text>We killed your spy as it was trying to steal from us. From my experience, it is far less dangerous to read a book and try to learn something yourself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_KILLED_MY_SPY_1">
			<Text>I regret any confusion caused by our late agent's recent activity. Please let any hostile feelings rest with the deceased operative.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CONFRONT_YOU_KILLED_MY_SPY_1">
			<Text>Hello there. Are you here about that little spying incident?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SUSPECT_YOU_OF_SPYING_1">
			<Text>One of my cities was recently burglarized and technological secrets were stolen. May I be assured that you had nothing to do with this?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SUSPECT_YOU_OF_SPYING_2">
			<Text>I'm convinced you've been spying on my great civilization. You should stop before somebody gets hurt.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_STOP_CONVERSIONS_1">
			<Text>We have taken notice of the religious conversions you are undertaking inside our empire. We must ask you to cease this activity immediately!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_HUMAN_KILLED_MY_SPY_UNFORGIVEN_1">
			<Text>I understand that some actions may not be forgiven.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_HUMAN_KILLED_MY_SPY_FORGIVEN_1">
			<Text>It makes me glad that you will overlook this awkward circumstance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you agreed to end this proselytizing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_BAD_1">
			<Text>Your religious fervor is unsettling.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_AGREE_1">
			<Text>As you wish, our missionaries will no longer share the one true faith with the people in your cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_DISAGREE_1">
			<Text>In spite of your protests, your citizens will continue to be enlightened by our missionaries, even though you damn your own people to live in ignorance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_1">
			<Text>We are eagerly anticipating your unconditional surrender.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_2">
			<Text>Your complete capitulation sounds reasonable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_3">
			<Text>We can make a deal now to forestall your utter annihilation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_LIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>We were very pleased to hear your recent proposal to the {1_LeagueName}.  It seems that our goals are aligned.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_LIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} suits our interests quite nicely.  You have our sincere gratitude.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_DISLIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} is a blatant attack on our interests.  I hope this does not escalate to future conflict.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_DISLIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>I found your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} very troubling.  Surely there is a better way to resolve our differences than petty politics.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Thanks to the help of your delegates, our recent proposal to the {1_LeagueName} was successful.  We look forward to your continued support, and will try to return the favor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Our proposal to the {1_LeagueName} succeeded, with the support of your delegation.  Together we can accomplish many great things.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_FOILED_OUR_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Your delegation played a part in the failure of our proposal to the {1_LeagueName}.  I do not take such transgressions lightly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_FOILED_OUR_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Our proposal to the {1_LeagueName} was defeated at the hands of your delegates.  Do not expect our delegation to support your interests in the future.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_HOSTING_1">
			<Text>We thank you for entrusting the World Congress to our capable leadership.  I expect great things to come in the {1_LeagueName}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Responses to player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>We'll see about that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Yes, that's right.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>I remain confident that my decision was the best for my people and my nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HUMAN_BULLIED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Very well. I'll be monitoring the situation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_TRADE_CANT_MATCH_OFFER_1">
			<Text>We are not willing to offer you enough to make this a fair trade.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_TRADE_CANT_MATCH_OFFER_2">
			<Text>Any deal we suggest would result in an unfair exchange for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGINGX_1">
			<Text>We've noticed that you've been looking for cultural artifacts within our borders. This needs to stop.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGING_DISAGREE_1">
			<Text>Sorry, our plans are too important to be stopped over a trinket.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGING_AGREE_1">
			<Text>As you wish, we will stop looking for artifacts within your borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_DIGGING_BAD_1">
			<Text>Do I have to escalate this?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_DIGGING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Thank you for heeding our request. An artifact discovered on our land belongs to our people, not yours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DIPLO_DISCUSS_DONT_STOP_DIGGING">
			<Text>I'll dig wherever I want, for the sake of art.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DIPLO_DISCUSS_STOP_DIGGING">
			<Text>I just thought your cultural heritage would look better in one of my castles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>My people have been corrupted by your false ideals of freedom and equality. When will you learn that you cannot have both!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_ORDER_1">
			<Text>Your socialist propaganda has turned my own workers against me. Now how am I to complete my master projects?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>I believe in certain virtues to be the inalienable rights of my people. But your propaganda has brainwashed them into believing they must be indentured to the state.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>Your people have seen the liberties enjoyed in Bavaria. They are not intimidated by your backwards thinking. They will rise up against you if you do not give them Freedom.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_ORDER_1">
			<Text>Your workers live in such deplorable conditions, it is no wonder they no clamour for Order.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>Your unbounded thinking has made your people undignified and selfish. Abolish their civil liberties, and join the way of Autocracy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SWITCHED_TO_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you've switched to Freedom. There is no greater way to enjoy beauty than by doing so without fear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SWITCHED_TO_ORDER_1">
			<Text>Adopting Order was something that I could not avoid. So many projects, so many workers. I'm sure you know what I mean.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_SWITCHED_TO_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>You'll soon see the benefits of switching to Autocracy. No more ministers bemoaning your flagrant spending. No more worries. It's heaven.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>I'm pleased to see that your people can't get enough of my fantasy castles. They're simply flocking to Bavaria! I'll have to set up a bed and breakfast soon.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>