<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/26/2013 9:33:44 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SERBIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SERBIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Following their settlement in the Balkans, Serbs established several states in the early Middle Ages. The Serbian Kingdom obtained recognition by Rome and Constantinople in 1217; the state was elevated to the Serbian Empire, in 1346. By the mid-16th century, the entire territory of modern-day Serbia was annexed by the Ottoman Empire, at times interrupted by the Habsburgs. In the early 19th century, the Serbian revolution established the nation-state as the region's first constitutional monarchy, which subsequently expanded its territory and pioneered the abolition of feudalism in the Balkans.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Following disastrous casualties in World War I, and subsequent unification of Habsburg crownlands of Vojvodina and Syrmia with Serbia, the country co-founded Yugoslavia with other South Slavic peoples, which would exist in various formations until 2006, when Montenegro declared its independence.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SERBIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Geography</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SERBIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				Located at the crossroads between Central and Southern Europe, Serbia is found in the Balkan peninsula and the Pannonian Plain. The Pannonian Plain covers the northern third of the country (mainly Vojvodina and Macva) while the easternmost tip of Serbia extends into the Wallachian Plain. The terrain of central part of the country, with the region of Sumadija at its heart, consists chiefly of hills traversed by the rivers. Mountains dominate the southern third of Serbia. There are 377 protected areas of Serbia, encompassing 4,947 square kilometers or 6.4% of the country. One notable exception is the Pcinja which flows into the Aegean Sea.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SERBIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Environment</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SERBIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>
				With 29.1% of its territory covered by forest, Serbia is considered to be a middle-forested country. Forest coverage is, when compared on a global scale, similar to world forest coverage which accounts for 30%, but it is somewhat lower than the European average of 35%. Serbia is a country of rich ecosystem and species diversity – covering only 1.9% of the whole European territory Serbia is home to 39% of European vascular flora, 51% of European fish fauna, 40% of European reptile and amphibian fauna, 74% of European bird fauna, 67% European mammal fauna. It's abundance of mountains and rivers make it an ideal environment for a variety of animals, many of which are protected including wolves, lynx, bears, foxes and stags. Mountain of Tara in western Serbia is one of the last regions in Europe where bears can still live in absolute freedom. There are 377 protected areas of Serbia, encompassing 4,947 square kilometers or 6.4% of the country.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Stephen Uros IV Dusan, commonly known as Stephen Dusan and Dusan the Mighty, was the King of Serbia and Emperor of the Serbs from 16 April 1346 until his death on 20 December 1355. Dusan managed to conquer a large part of Southeast Europe, becoming one of the most powerful monarchs in his time. He enacted the constitution of the Serbian Empire in Dusan's Code, one of, if not the most important work of medieval Serbia. Dusan promoted the Serbian Church from an archbishopric to a patriarchate, finished the construction of the Visoki Decani-monastery, and founded the Saint Archangels Monastery, among others. Under his rule Serbia reached its territorial, economical, political and cultural peak.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Uros IV Dusan was the eldest son of King Uros III of Decani and Theodora Smilets, the daughter of emperor Smilets of Bulgaria. He was born in ca. 1308, in Serbia, but with his fathers exile in 1314, the family lives in Constantinople until 1320, when his father is pardoned and allowed to return. Right after the battle of Velbazhd, Uros III had the chance to attack the Byzantines, but he chose not to, resulting in the alienation of many nobles, who sought to expand to the south. By January or February 1331, Dusan was quarreling with his father, perhaps pressured by the nobility. According to contemporary pro-Dusan sources, evil advisors turned Uros III against his son; he decided to seize and exclude Dusan of his inheritance. Uros III sent an army into Zeta against his son, the army ravaged Skadar, but Dusan had crossed the Bojana. A brief period of anarchy in parts of Serbia took place, before the father and son concluded peace in April 1331. Three months later, Uros III ordered Dusan to meet him. Dusan feared for his life and his advisors persuaded him to resist, so Dusan marched from Skadar to Nerodimlje, where he besieged his father. Uros III fled, and Dusan captured the treasury and family.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Dusan made peace with Ivan Alexander of Bulgaria because he wanted to move against the richer Byzantium. In the first years of his reign, Dusan started to fight against the Byzantine Empire (1334), and warfare continued with interruptions of various duration until his death in 1355. Twice he became involved in larger conflicts with the Hungarians, but these clashes were mostly defensive. Dusan's systematic offensive began in 1342 and in the end he conquered all Byzantine territories in the western Balkans as far as Kavala, except for the Peloponnesus and Thessaloniki, which he could not conquer because he had too small of a fleet. In 1343, he added "of Romans (Greeks)" to his self-styled title "King of Serbia, Albania and the coast". In 1345 he began calling himself tsar, equivalent of Emperor. Dusan sought to obtain Constantinople, but died prematurely at Devoll on 20 December 1355.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_LIVED">
			<Text>1308 - 1355 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_NAME">
			<Text>Stephen Uros IV Dusan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of the Serbs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_TITLES_1">
			<Text>King of Serbia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Emperor of the Serbs and Greeks</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_UROS_IV_TITLES_3">
			<Text>Dusan the Mighty</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_DUSANS_CODE">
			<Text>Workers ignore terrain cost. Free Kefalija when founding a City, which can improve unimproved Mine Resources (+2 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold). Extra +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production from completed Policy Trees.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_DUSANS_CODE_SHORT">
			<Text>Artisans of Studenica</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_UROS_IV_FIRST_GREETING_1">
			<Text>An empire like you've never seen before. That is where you are right now: You have the honor of meeting the Emperor of the Serbs and Greeks!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_UROS_IV_FIRST_GREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome to Serbia. I am Stephen Dusan the Mighty, ..the Great, ..the Powerful, the Strong.., but simply 'tsar' will be fine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_UROS_IV_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Without a true leader, there is no Empire. I'll not wait for a disease to take my life; If I need to die, then let it be in an honourable fight!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_UROS_IV_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>I thought I was vigilant, but you knew exactly when to strike. I congratulate you, now leave me be.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>