<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by Pouakai -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--Unique Building-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MC_AYYUBID_MADRASAH">
			<Text>Madrasah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MC_AYYUBID_MADRASAH_HELP">
			<Text>+10% of [ICON_PEACE] Faith from this city contributes to [ICON_RESEARCH] Science.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+2 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science from Jungle tiles worked by this City.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a Library.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MC_AYYUBID_MADRASAH_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Madrasah is a Medieval-era building. It increases the science output of the city, and it's even more effective if the city is near to jungle tiles. The city must already have a Library in order to construct a Madrasah. It also provides additional [ICON_RESEARCH] Science equal to 10% of the [ICON_RESEARCH] Faith generated by the city, unlike the University which it replaces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MC_AYYUBID_MADRASAH_PEDIA">
			<Text>"Madrasah" is Arabic for any type of educational institution; although with a religious component, madrasahs were often secular, and could cover anything from elementary to higher learning. Usually associated with a mosque, madrasahs could even specialize in medicine, law, science, philosophy or the education of women. The first madrasah, the Gama'at al-Qarawiyyn, was established in 859 AD by Fatimah al-Fihri, the daughter of a wealthy merchant. During the rule of the Fatimid, Ayyubid and Mamluk dynasties, the practice of sponsoring madrasahs by the ruling, wealthy elite spread across Egypt and the Middle East. The first Ottoman madrasah was founded in 1331 AD in Iznik, and followed the traditions of Sunni Islam. The madrasahs of the Turks and Arabs would, as Europe suffered through the Dark Ages, keep the best of Western knowledge alive, and blended it with that of the East.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MC_AYYUBID_MADRASAH_SCIENCE">
			<Text>JFD: Madrasah Science</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MC_AYYUBID_MADRASAH_SCIENCE_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Unique Unit-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MC_AYYUBID_MAMELUKE">
			<Text>Mamluk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MC_AYYUBID_MAMELUKE_HELP">
			<Text>Religion-focused cavalry unit, only the Ayyubids may built it. When stationed in a city, prevents an enemy prophet or missionary from converting it. Ignores terrain penalties when in desert. Weak against Pikemen.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MC_AYYUBID_MAMELUKE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Mamluk is an Ayyubid Unique Unit with a strong religious focus. The Mamluk prevents enemy religious agents (Great Prophets and Missionaries) from converting a city whilst it is stationed inside. In addition, it also ignores terrain penalties when moving through desert and does not have a penalty when attacking cities, unlike the Knight which it replaces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_MC_AYYUBID_MAMELUKE_CIVILOPEDIA">
			<Text>The Mamluk (also spelt Mameluk, Mameluke and a variety of other ways) in Egypt were a military caste that originated in slave societies found throughout the Arabic world. In some cases, such as that of the Ayyubid dynasty, these soldiers, although slaves, attained very high positions in society, even being considered higher-ranking than free-born citizens of the sultanate. Their military prowess was world-renowned, and famously defeated both the Mongol horde and the Crusaders on a variety of occasions, thus securing their own holdings. In some cases, the Mamluk also rose up and took power for themselves, initiating Mamluk dynasties in Egypt and India. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_AYYUBID_MAMELUKE_IGNORES_TERRAIN_PENALTY">
			<Text>Ignores Terrain Cost in Desert</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_AYYUBID_MAMELUKE_IGNORES_TERRAIN_PENALTY_HELP">
			<Text>Ignores Terrain Cost in Desert</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Unique Ability-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LAND_OF_A_THOUSAND_MINARETS_SHORT">
			<Text>Amir al-Mu'minin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LAND_OF_A_THOUSAND_MINARETS">
			<Text>Receive free Mounted Units whenever a Great Prophet is born. These units earn [ICON_PEACE] Faith from kills, require no [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horses and cost no [ICON_GOLD] Gold maintenance. Conquered cities immediately convert to your religion on capture.</Text>
		</Row> 
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_CALIPHATE">
			<Text>A {1_UnitName} force has risen in the name of the holy Caliphate!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_CALIPHATE_SHORT">
			<Text>Armies arise in the name of the holy Caliphate!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_CALIPHATE">
			<Text>Al-Gazawat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_CALIPHATE_HELP">
			<Text>This unit heralds the forthcoming of a migthy Caliphate!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_AYYUBID_CALIPHATE">
			<Text>Al-Gazawat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_AYYUBID_CALIPHATE_HELP">
			<Text>Earns [ICON_PEACE] Faith from kills and costs no [ICON_GOLD] Gold maintenance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spy Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_0">
			<Text>Mohammed</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_1">
			<Text>Omar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_2">
			<Text>Youssef</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_3">
			<Text>Khaled</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_4">
			<Text>Mustafa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_5">
			<Text>Ahmed</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_6">
			<Text>Dina</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_7">
			<Text>Sara</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_8">
			<Text>Yasmin</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_9">
			<Text>Sofia</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!--Denonyms-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MC_AYYUBIDS_DESC">
			<Text>Ayyubid Dynasty</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MC_AYYUBIDS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>The Ayyubids</Text>
			<Plurality>2</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MC_AYYUBIDS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Ayyubid</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Civilopedias-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MC_AYYUBIDS">
			<Text>The Ayyubids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TITLE">
			<Text>The Ayyubid Dynasty</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Ayyubid dynasty was a Muslim dynasty of Kurdish origin. Founded by Saladin the dynasty claimed much of the Middle East during the 12th and 13th centuries. The family originally serves as soldiers to the Zengids until they were supplanted by Saladin. Within a decade of ascension Saladin expanded the Ayyubid state into modern day Syria, northern Mesopotamia, Hejaz, Yemen and the coast of North Africa up to Tunisia.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Climate and Terrain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Much of the territory of the Ayyubid state is inhospitable desert with fresh water sources scattered about the coasts. Centered in Egypt the Nile river cuts across the desert, splitting the Sahara from the entrance into the Middle East. Northern Africa charts many rivers along its coast up to modern day Tunisia, while the western Middle East is more mountainous and dotted with oases and lakes along the Mediterranean coast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Rawadiya Origins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The progenitor of the dynasty was Najm ad-Din Ayyub bin Shadhi. He belonged to a Kurdish tribe whose ancestors settled in Dvin in northern Armenia. He belonged to the Rawadiya tribe, a branch of the Hadhabani tribe. The Rawadiya were dominate in Dvin and were a member of the sedentary political-military elite of the town. Recent events in Dvin became unfavorable when Turkish generals seized the town from the Kurdish prince. Shadhi left with his two sons, Najm al-Din Ayyub and Asad ad-Din Shirkuh, for Iraq where he was greeted by his friend Mujahhed al-Din Bihruz - the military governor of northern Mesopotamia under the Seljuks. Bihruz appointed Shadhi as the governor of Tikrit; after Shadhi's death Ayyub took his father's place and retained his brother for assistance. Together they managed the city well, gaining popularity from the locals.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Meanwhile the ruler of Mosul, Imad ad-Din Zangi was defeated by the forces of the Abbasids under al-Mustarshid and the other forces of Bihruz. In his attempt to escape to Mosul Zangi past Tikrit and took shelter with Ayyub. Zangi sought Ayyub's assistance in his escape; he complied and provided Zangi and his companions boats to cross the Tigris river to the safety of Mosul. As a consequence Ayyub was put to task by the Abbasid authorities, simultaneously in an unrelated incident Shirkuh killed a close confidant of Bihruz on charges that he sexually assaulted a woman in Tikrit. Both brothers were issued arrest warrants by the Abbasid court, but before they were arrested they left Tikrit for Mosul in 1138. Upon arrival Zangi repaid his debt to them by providing all they required, Zangi even recruited the brothers into his service; Ayyub was made a commander of Ba'albek and Shirkuh entered the service on Zangi's son, Nur ad-Din.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_4">
			<Text>From Anarchy to Dynasty</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_4">
			<Text>In 1164 Nur al-Din sent Shirkuh to lead an expeditionary force to stop Crusader influence and dominance in and increasingly restless Egypt. Shirkuh enlisted his brother's son Saladin, as an officer under his command. They drove out Dirgham, the vizier of Egypt, and reinstalled he predecessor Shawar; Shawar ordered the withdrawal of Shirkuh and his forces from Egypt, but he refused, claiming the will of Nur al-Din. Thus for the next few years Shirkuh and Saladin continued to defeat both the forces of the Crusaders and Shawar, claiming Bilbais, then a site near Giza, and Alexandria when Saladin stayed to protect it while Shirkuh continued into Lower Egypt. Shawar died in 1169 and Shirkuh became vizier there, but he too fell later that year, leaving Saladin as the next vizier; he was appointed by the Fatimid caliph al-Adid because there was "no one weaker or younger" and "not one of the emirs obeyed him or served him".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Saladin reached a point of great independence, much to the dismay of Nur al-Din; he attempted to influence events in Egypt by allowing Saladin's elder brother, Turan-Shah to supervise Saladin as a way to cause dissension in the Ayyubid family and undermine its position in Egypt. Nur al-Din met Saladin's request to see his father Ayyub, however he was sent primarily to ensure that the Abbasid suzerainty was proclaimed in Egypt, which Saladin was not willing to easily undertake since he was vizier to the Fatimids. While Nur al-Din failed to actually provoke the Ayyubids, the extended family were not entirely behind Saladin, especially local governors in Syria. Saladin consolidated his control in Egypt after ordering Turan-Shah to put down a revolt stages by the Fatimid army in Cairo, after this success he began to grant his family high-ranking positions in the country and increased the Sunni influence in Cairo by commissioning the construction for the Maliki branch of Sunni Islam in Cairo and one for the Shafi'i denomination in al-Fustat. In 1171 al-Adid died and Saladin took complete advantage of the power vacuum, seizing control the country. When he seized power Saladin switched Egypt's allegiance to the Abbasid Caliphate which adhered to Sunni Islam.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Saladin's Expansion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Under the new state of Ayyubid rule Saladin went to Alexandria in 1171-2, where he was troubled by having so many followers and such little money there. A family council of the Ayyubid emirs was held there where it was decided that Saladin's nephew, al-Muzaffar Taqi al-Din Umar would launch an expedition to the coastal region of Barqa with a force of 500 cavalry. To justify the raid a letter was sent to the Bedouin tribes there, rebuking them for the robberies of travelers and requiring them to pay the alms-tax, the latter was to be paid from their livestock. In late 1172 Aswan was besieged by former Fatimid soldiers from Nubia. Kanz al-Dawla, the governor of Aswan and a former Fatimid loyalist requested reinforcements from Saladin. He complied and sent them to Aswan, however by the time they arrived the Nubian forces already left. Under Turan-Shah, however, the Ayyubids continued on in fact conquer northern Nubia claim Ibrim where the Auyyubid forces lived for the duration of their campaign. From Ibrim they raiding the surrounding region and only stopped after being presented with an armistice from the Nubian king. Originally suspicious and hawkish in response, Turan-Shah sent an envoy to Dongola, the residence of the Nubian king. The envoy returned describing the poverty of both Dongola and Nubia as a whole. Thus the Ayyubids asked Nubia to guarantee the protection of Aswan and Upper Egypt, but were ultimately discouraged from further expansion due to Nubia's poverty. In 1174 Sharaf al-Din Qaraqush, a commander under Taqi al-Din Umar conquered Tripoli from the Nomads with an army of Turks and Bedouins.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]For a more detailed look into Saladin's conquests see his Civilopedia entry. Along with these conquests in North Africa and Nubia, Saladin would continue his expansion to essentially the end of his life; Saladin pressed on into the Middle East to claim areas of Arabia, Syria, Mesopotamia, Palestine and Transjordan. Saladin's military career and life ended at the end the Third Crusade were the Ayyubids suffered losses near Acre, Jaffa and a good deal of Palestine. Saladin signed a peace treaty with Richard the Lionhearted to restore the Kingdom of Jerusalem between Jaffa and Beirut before he died in 1193.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Quarrels over the Sultanate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Rather than establishing a centralized empire, Saladin instead created a hereditary ownership throughout his lands, dividing his empire among the kinsmen, with family members receiving semi-autonomous fiefs and principalities. While the princes owed allegiance to the Ayyubid sultan, in their own territories they were more or less independent. Upon Saladin's death his son, az-Zahir took Aleppo from Saladin's brother, al-Adil per arrangement, and al-Aziz Uthman held Cairo while his eldest son, al-Afdal retained Damascus; at the time it also included Palestine and a great deal of Lebanon. Al-Adil acquired northern Mesopotamia, known as al-Jazira, and held the Zengids at bay in Mosul. In 1193 Mas'ud of Mosul allied with Zangi of Sinjar and together they moved to occupy as much of al-Jazira as possible, but before any major results could be achieved Mas'ud fell ill and returned to Mosul. Thus al-Adil compelled Zangi to make a hasty peace before the Zengids suffered loss of territory to the Ayyubids. Al-Adil's son, al-Mu'azzam took Karak and Transjordan.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Eventually Saladin's sons began competing over the division of the empire. Before his death Saladin appointed his son, al-Afdal as the governor of Damascus to ensure that his son should continue to see the city as his principal residence, to emphasize the primacy of the jihad - 'holy struggle' - against the Crusader states. This arrangement in fact led to his undoing; several of his father's subordinate emirs left Damascus to reach Cairo to lobby al-Aziz Uthman to oust him on claims he was inexperienced and intended to sweep out the old Ayyubid guard. In 1194 Uthman demanded the sultanate, he was compelled to do so by al-Adil before al-Afdal's incompetence put the empire in jeopardy. Al-Aziz Uthman's claim was realized after a series of assaults in Damascus in 1196, forcing al-Afdal to leave for a less lofty position in Salkhad. Al-Adil established himself as a lieutenant of al-Aziz Uthman but in his own rite wielded a good deal of influence. When al-Aziz Uthman died in an accident near Cairo, al-Afdal returned to the sultan position due to al-Adil's absence in a campaign. Upon al-Adil's return he managed to occupy the Citadel of Damascus, but then met the strong forces of both al-Afdal and his brother az-Zahir. Under al-Afdal's command the two forces fell and by 1200 al-Adil returned to the offensive.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By Uthman's death two mamluk clans in the empire opposed each other; the Asadiyya and the Salahiyya. Al-Adil backed the Salahiyya in his attacks against al-Afdal, with their aid he conquered Cairo in 1200 and forced al-Afdal to accept banishment. Al-Adil proclaimed himself Sultan of Egypt and Syria and entrusted al-Mu'azzam with the governance of Damascus and his son al-Kamil the governance of al-Jazira. The same year a sharif - 'tribal head' - Qatada ibn Idris captured Mecca and was recognized as the emir there by al-Adil. Al-Afdal again sought to reclaim Damascus once more but failed, al-Adil entered the city in triumph in 1201. Az-Zahir still held Aleppo, so al-Afdal was given Samosata in Anatolia. Now al-Adil's line would dominate the next half a century of Ayyubid rule, as opposed to Saladin's line. Al-Adil redistributed his possessions between his sons; al-Kamil would succeed him in Egypt, al-Ashraf gained al-Jazira and al-Awhad was given Diyar Bakr, the latter-most fell into al-Ashraf's control when al-Awhad died. Al-Adil provoked open hostility with the Hanbali "lobby" in Damascus for essentially ignoring the Crusaders; he only launched one campaign against them and felt that their army was invisible in a straight fight. A prolonged campaign also needed a lasting unified Arab coalition, the Ayyubid state at this time was somewhat unstable with the in-fighting. Al-Adil was focused on a steady growth of the empire, mainly by expanding Ayyubid authority in al-Jazira and Armenia. The Abbasids eventually recognized al-Adil's position as sultan in 1207.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A Crusader campaign was launched on November 3, 1217 with a strike towards Transjordan. Al-Mu'azzam urged al-Adil to launch a counter-attack but he refused. The following year the fortress of Damietta was besieged by the Crusaders; after two failed attempts the fortress capitulated on August 26. Less than a week later al-Adil died, apparently by shock. Al-Kamil became sultan in Cairo with his brother al-Mu'azzam claiming the throne of Damascus. Unlike his fearful father, al-Kamil attempted to retake the fortress, but was repelled by John of Brienne. After learning of a conspiracy against him he fled Cairo, leaving the army leaderless. Panic quickly spread, but with the help of al-Mu'azzam, al-Kamil regrouped his forces. However, by then the Crusaders captured his camp. The Ayyubids offered to negotiate the withdrawal from Damietta, offering to restore Palestine and the Kingdom of Jerusalem, with the exception of the forts of Mont Real and Karak. Pelagius of Albano, the leader of the Fifth Crusade refused, and in 1221 he and the Crusaders were driven out of the Nile Delta after the Ayyubid victory at Mansura.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Disintegration and Downfall</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT_7">
			<Text>After the victory, however, the Ayyubid state entered a decline that it never truly recovered from. Encroaching rivals and local dynasties began to appear and challenge the state as al-Kamil and al-Mu'azzam fought amongst themselves and the Crusader threat continued to add pressure on the dynasty. In the east the Khwarezemids under Jalal ad-Din Mingburnu captured Khilat from al-Ashraf, as the normally loyalist Rasulids assaulted Ayyubid Arabia. In 1222 the Ayyubids appointed their leader, Ali Bin Rasul as governor of Mecca. In 1224 the local al-Yamani dynasty gained control of Hadramaut from the Ayyubids, following the Yemeni governor's death in 1229 Nur ad-Din Umar declared himself the independent ruler of Yemen and stopped paying tribute to Egypt. The Holy Roman Emperor Frederick II launched the Sixth Crusade to add fuel to the strife between al-Kamil and al-Mu'azzam. To avoid a Syrian attack against Egypt al-Kamil offered Jerusalem to Frederick, but he refused, however al-Kamil's position was strengthened with the death of al-Mu'azzam in 1227. He continued negotiating with Frederick in Acre the following year, he managed to establish a limited truce on February 1229. The truce ceded Jerusalem unfortified to the Crusader for over a decade, although Muslims were to still hold control over Islamic holy sites. Militarily the truce was meaningless, nevertheless an-Nasir Dawud used it to provoke the Syrian citizens and a Friday sermon by a popular preacher "reduced the crowd to violent sobbing and tears." The settlement also came with a new division of the principalities; Damascus and its territories would go to al-Ashraf while maintaining al-Kamil's sovereignty. An-Nasir Dawud resisted this and he and al-Kamil fought at Damascus as the latter sent forces to enforce the settlement in May 1229. Despite the citizens rallying to an-Nasir Dawud, after a month of fighting he sued for peace and he was given a new principality centered in Karak as al-Ashraf became the governor of Damascus.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]More threats emerged; the Seljuks made their way into al-Jazira and descendants of Qatada ibn Idris fought with Ayyubid overlords over control of Mecca. To add the their strains the Rasulids of Yemen attempted to end Ayyubid suzerainty in the Hejaz to take control of the region, which they did in 1238 when Nur al-Din Umar captured Mecca. Finally the greatest problem so far had surfaced; the emirs of Syria sought to assert their independence from Cairo, as the sons of al-Kamil, as-Salih Ayyub, and al-Ashraf, as-Salih Ismail, fought between each other they each even sought the alliance of the Crusaders against the other. In 1244, the breakaway Syrian Ayyubids allied with the Crusaders to fight the Egyptian Ayyubids allied with the Khwarizmids near Gaza, in one of the Ayyubids largest battles in its history as-Salih Ayyub won the major victory and as a result created a virtual collapse of the Kingdom of Jerusalem. Ayyub continued to press on into Syria and reclaim the former land, the last place that held Ismail's influence fell to Ayyub in December 1246. By May the following year, with the exception of Aleppo, all of Syria was reclaimed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Ayyubids were still in the grips of Crusader pressure and eventually a new threat appeared from the east, one the cost them their dynasty; the undefeated Mongols. Before the Mongol intervention, the Ayyubid sultan alienated the Mamluks after their victories in battle and constantly threatened by him. Fearing their positions the Bahri Mamluks revolted and killed him in April 1250. The independent Aleppo enlisted all the Syrian Ayyubid princes to a common cause against as-Salih Ayyub's Egypt, the governor of Aleppo, an-Nasir Yusuf capitalized on the death of their sultan and the Mamluk rebellion. While maintaining a large force against the Mamluks Yusuf's army fell to Aibek, the Mamluk leader who took the throne upon the revolution. In the battles that followed the two sides realized the Crusaders would greatly benefit the most from the war, thus the two leaders met and accepted a treaty granting the Mamluks retention of Egypt and Palestine, ending Ayyubid rule over Egypt. The treaty did not last long and after a second treaty was signed, by December 11, 1256 both sultans send requests to the Abbasids in Baghdad to seek formal investment from him. An-Nasir Yusuf sent an embassy to Karakorum in 1250 shortly after assuming power. However the Khan Möngke issued an order to his brother Hulagu to expend to the Nile. Hulagu sacked Baghdad in 1258 and killed the Abbasid caliph, later in the year the Ayyubids lost Diyar Bakr to the Mongols. They continued to press on into Aleppo, sacking the city a causing great panic in Syria. The emir of Homs sought to ally with the Mongols, they allowed it and he was able to continue his governance, Hama also capitulated without resistance but did not ally with the Mongols. Hulagu decided to leave mid-campaign to Karakorum and left Kitbuqa, a Christian general to carry on with the conquest. Damascus capitulated but was not sacked like the other Muslim cities. From Gaza an-Nasir Yusuf managed to incite the small garrison in the Citadel of Damascus to rebel the Mongols, they reacted with a swift artillery attack and retained the city. The Mongols continued to Samaria and as far south as Gaza unhindered. They captured an-Nasir Yusur was captured there and was used to persude the garrison at Ajlun to also capitulate. The junior governor of Banias allied with the Mongols and effectively ended Ayyubid power in both the region and history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_STATBOX">
			<Text>[NEWLINE]        Leader: Saladin[NEWLINE]        Unique Unit: Mamluk[NEWLINE]        Unique Building: Madrasah[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_FACTOID_HEADING">
			<Text>Ayyubid Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_MC_AYYUBIDS_FACTOID_TEXT">
			<Text>Despite the ongoing war with the Crusaders, it did not prevent the development of good commercial relations with Europe. The major factor to this was the new interests the Europeans developed when coming into contact with the Muslims. Everything from commodities to new fashions and furnishings, and eastern works of art.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City List-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_CAIRO">
			<Text>Cairo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_DVIN">
			<Text>Dvin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_BAALBEK">
			<Text>Baalbek</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_BILBAIS">
			<Text>Bilbais</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_ALEXANDRIA">
			<Text>Alexandria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_ASWAN">
			<Text>Aswan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_ZABID">
			<Text>Zabid</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_TAIZZ">
			<Text>Taizz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_SANAA">
			<Text>Sanaa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_YANBU">
			<Text>Yanbu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_HAMA">
			<Text>Hama</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_HOMS">
			<Text>Homs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_TELL_AL_SULTAN">
			<Text>Tell al-Sultan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_MAARRAT_AL_NU_MAN">
			<Text>Maarrat al-Nu'man</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_AZAZ">
			<Text>Azaz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_BAZAA">
			<Text>Baza'a</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_MANBIJ">
			<Text>Manbij</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_QUS">
			<Text>Qus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_KAWKAB_ALHAWA">
			<Text>Kawkab al-Hawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_ALEPPO">
			<Text>Aleppo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_HARIM">
			<Text>Harim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_NABLUS">
			<Text>Nablus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_TIBERIAS">
			<Text>Tiberias</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_KAFR_SABT">
			<Text>Kafr Sabt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_ACRE">
			<Text>Acre</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_NAZARETH">
			<Text>Nazareth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_SAFFURIYA">
			<Text>Saffuriya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_HAIFA">
			<Text>Haifa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_SEBASTIA">
			<Text>Sebastia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_JAFFA">
			<Text>Jaffa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_SAREPTA">
			<Text>Sarepta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_BEIRUT">
			<Text>Beirut</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_JABLEH">
			<Text>Jableh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_RAMLA">
			<Text>Ramla</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_DARUM">
			<Text>Darum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_BAYT_JIBRIN">
			<Text>Bayt Jibrin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_LATRUN">
			<Text>Latrun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_ASCALON">
			<Text>Ascalon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_KARAK">
			<Text>Karak</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_MC_AYYUBIDS_SAFED">
			<Text>Safed</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Leader Civlopedia Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_DESC">
			<Text>Saladin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_LIVED">
			<Text>c. 1137 - 1193</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_NAME">
			<Text>Saladin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Sultan of the Ayyubids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Sultan of Egypt and Sham</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TITLES_2">
			<Text>The King Strong to Aid</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Salah ad-Din Yusuf ibn Ayyub was the founder of the Ayyubid dynasty and the first sultan of Egypt and Syria. Saladin led the opposition against the Crusaders in the Levant and led the new Muslim state to its zenith in power and territory. Within the Fatimid government in Egypt before, Saladin rose up the ranks with his victories against the Europeans and his influence with caliph al-Adid. His noble and chivalrous demeanor was noted even by the Christian chroniclers, and despite being the Crusaders nemesis he won the respect of many of them, including Richard the Lionhearted.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Born in Tikrit in Mesopotamia, Saladin was born as simply Yusuf ibn Ayyub. His family was Kurdish, originating from the village of Ajdanakan near Dvin. Five years before Yusuf's birth, the army of Imad ad-Din Zengi retreated to Mosul but found their path blocked by the Tigris river. Zengi and the party made for Tikrit where Najm ad-Din Ayyub, Saladin's father served as a warden. Ayyub provided ferries and allowed Zengi refuge in Tikrit. In the year of Saladin's birth Mujahed ad-Din Bihruz reprimanded Najm ad-Din Ayyub for Zengi's refuge and banished him from the town. It is alleged that on the ferry the Ayyub family left on was where Saladin was born. In 1139 the Ayyub family moved into Mosul when the appreciative Imad ad-Din Zengi acknowledged his debt and appointed Najm ad-Din Ayyub the commander of his fortress in Baalbek. After Zengi's death in 1146 his son, Nur ad-Din became the regent of Aleppo and led the Zengids. Now in Damascus, Saladin had a fondness for the city, however little else is known of his early childhood. He was able to answer questions on Euclid, the Almagest, arithmetic and law, but it was his study of the Qur'an and the "sciences of religion" that connected him to his contemporaries. During his studies he took a greater interest in religion than the army. Another possible effect on his youth and love of religion may had been the recent events; the First Crusade was launched and Jerusalem was taken in a surprise attack. As well as Islam Saladin had a working knowledge of the genealogies, biographies and histories of the Arabs, and the bloodlines of Arabian horses.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>First Expeditions</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Saladin's career in the military began under the tuition of Asad al-Din Shirkuh, a military commander under Nur ad-Din - Emir of Damascus and Aleppo, a member of the Zengid dynasty and the most influential teacher of Saladin. In 1163 Fatimid caliph al-Adid's vizier, Shawar was driven out of Egypt by his rival Dirgham, a member of the Banu Ruzzaik tribe. Shawar asked for military backing from Nur ad-Din, complying in the following year by sending Shirkuh and Saladin. When Shawar was reinstalled he demanded that Shirkuh withdraw from Egypt for 30,000 dinars, but he refused insisting Nur ad-Din's will to remain. In the prior and ensuing battles Saladin's roles were minor, in the fight against Shawar he was ordered to collect the stores from Bilbais before its attack by a combined force of Crusaders and Egyptians.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the sacking of the city the two forces again engaged in battle on the desert border of the Nile, west of Giza. This time Saladin played a major role in marshalling the right wing of the combined army of Zengid and Kurdish forces. The Europeans enjoyed early success against Shirkuh's men but their horses found the field too hilly and sandy to cope. Hugh of Caesarea, commander of the Crusaders was captured by Saladin's troop. The Zengids won the battle and Saladin won credit for helping his mentor Shirkuh in one the "most remarkable victories in recorded history", according to historian Ali ibn al-Athir, yet more of Shirkuh's men fell and the battle is not considered a total victory to most. The two pressed on to Alexandria where they were welcomed and given money, arms and a base. However, facing a new and superior coalition force who tried to besiege the city, Shirkuh split his force and took the bulk of his men out of Alexandria and charged Saladin and the rest of the men to guard the city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Saladin's Egypt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Shirkuh was in a power struggle with Shawar and Amalric I of the Kingdom of Jerusalem, where Shawar asked for Amalric's aid. In 1169 Saladin assassinated Shawar and Shirkuh also died later that year. Nur ad-Din chose Shirkuh's successor but caliph al-Adid appointed Saladin to replace Shawar as vizier. It is not entirely known why the Shia caliph appointed the Sunni Saladin; Ali ibn al-Athir claims he was chosen because his advisers state that "there was no one weaker or younger" and "not one of the emirs obeyed him." According to this theory, after some bargaining he was eventually accepted by most of the emirs. Saladin became Emir of Egypt on March 26, 1169. With his newfound independence Saladin was still at grips with the issue of loyalty between the caliph al-Adid and the leader Nur ad-Din. Nur ad-Din alleged did not like this and was hostile towards Saladin's appointment, quoted to have said "how dare he do anything without my orders?" He wrote several angry letters to Saladin, who dismissed them and did not abandon his allegiance with Nur ad-Din.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Later that year Egyptian soldiers and emirs attempted to assassinate Saladin, but his intelligence chief, Ali bin Safyan informed him of the plot, and thus Saladin had the mastermind, Mu'tamin al-Khilafa - the controller of the Fatimid Palace - arrested and killed. The next day African soldiers from the Fatimid army and Egyptian emirs and civilians stages a revolt. By August 23 Saladin quelled the unrest and as a result never faced a military challenge from Cairo. Near the end of the year Saladin, with forces from Nur ad-Din, defeated a large Crusader-Byzantine force near Damietta. In the spring of 1170 Nur ad-Din sent Saladin's father to Egypt as requested by Saladin, and encouragement from the Abbasid caliph al-Mustanjid, who was attempting to pressure Saladin in deposing his rival caliph al-Adid. Saladin strengthened his hold on Egypt by granting his family member high-ranking positions in the region, increasing the Sunni influence in Cairo by building a college for the Maliki branch of Sunni Islam there. Saladin also launched a campaign against the Crusaders with a strike against Darum in 1170. Amalric withdrew from the garrison from Gaza to defend Darum, but Saladin evaded them and instead attacked Gaza. He destroyed the outer town around the castle and killed most of its citizens after they were refused entry into the castle. In the same year Saladin captured the castle of Eilat, built on an island off the Gulf of Aqaba. It was never a threat to the Muslim navy but could harass smaller ships, Saladin chose to take it and clear it from his path.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Nur ad-Din is said to have wrote to Saladin in June 1171 to tell him to reestablish the Abbasid caliphate in Egypt, which Saladin coordinated two months later after more encouragement by Najm ad-Din al-Khabushani, a Shafi'i faqih - an expert in Islamic law - who opposed Shia rule in the country. Several Egyptian emirs were killed, but al-Adid was told that they were killed for rebelling against him. Al-Adid then fell ill, or was poisoned according to one account, and asked Saladin to visit him so al-Adid would request that he take care of his children. Saladin refused, however, fearing treachery from the Abbasids. Al-Adid died on September 13, 1171 and five days later the Abbasid khutba - a formal procession or preaching - was pronounced in Cairo and al-Fustat, proclaiming al-Mustadi as caliph. The proclamation made official the ending of the Fatimid rule over Egypt and thus established a new dynasty, the Ayyubid dynasty.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Brief Interim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Just one week after the establishment of the Ayyubid dynasty Saladin left Cairo to participate in the joint attack on the desert castles of Kerak and Montreal in the Kingdom of Jerusalem, with Nur ad-Din attacking from Syria. Before reaching there however Saladin withdrew, he realized that if he met Nur ad-Din at Shaubak he would refuse Saladin to return to Egypt due to Nur ad-Din continued reluctance to consolidate such a great deal of territory to Saladin. Also, the kingdom provided a buffer between Saladin and Nur ad-Din, without it it would give Nur ad-Din the opportunity to annex Egypt. Saladin claimed he withdrew to tend to Fatimid plots against him but Nur ad-Din was not pleased and did not accept the excuse. In the summer of 1172 a Nubian army and a party of Armenian refugees were discovered on the Egyptian border preparing an attack against Aswan. The emir of Aswan asked for Saladin's aid, he provided reinforcements under command of Saladin's brother, Turan-Shah. The Nubians were no match, they left their encampment only to return the following year to be driven back a second time. To respond to this Nubian threat the Egyptians advanced and captured the town of Ibrim.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]One and a half years after caliph al-Adid's death, while Nur ad-Din had not taken action against Saladin, he expected a return of the 200,000 dinars he invested into Shirkuh's army that led to his and Saladin's seizure of Egypt. Saladin paid him with 60,000 dinars, "wonderful manufactured goods", jewels, an ass of the finest breed and an elephant. En route to sending these to Damascus Saladin took the opportunity to raid the Crusader countryside. He did not actually press an attack on the castles but rather he attempted to drive out the Bedouins there to rob the Franks of guides of the region. On the last day of July 1173 Saladin's father was injured in a horse-riding accident, which led to his death nine days later. The following year Saladin sent Turan-Shah to conquer Yemen to allocate it and the port Aden to the Ayyubid dynasty. Yemen would also serve as an emergence territory lest Nur ad-Din attempt a successful invasion of Egypt.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_6">
			<Text>The Taking of Syria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_6">
			<Text>In the early summer of 1174 Nur ad-Din began to marshal an army, sending summons to Mosul, Diyarbakir and al-Jazira to prepare for an attack against Saladin and Egypt. The Ayyubids held a council upon discovering this to discuss the threat. Yet on May 15 that year Nur ad-Din died after being poisoned a week before, his throne was given to his eleven year old son as-Salih Ismail al-Malik. Saladin sent a letter to as-Salih stating that he promised to "act as a sword" to his enemies and spoke of the death of Nur ad-Din as as "earthquake shock." In the wake of Nur ad-Din's death Saladin faced a difficult decision; he could move his army against the Crusaders from Egypt or wait for an invitation by as-Salih to come to Syria to aid him and launch a war there. Saladin could also endeavour to annex Syria before it could pose a serious threat, especially in the hands of a rival. Doing so, however, posed a risk; Saladin feared that attacking a land belonging to his master could portray him as a hypocrite, as doing so is forbidden from the Islamic principles he followed, and as a result unsuitable to lead a war against the Crusaders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Therefore, Saladin saw that in order to gain Syria he needed either an invitation from as-Salih or to warn him of potential anarchy and danger from the Crusaders that may rise. When as-Salih was removed to Aleppo in August, Gumushtigin, the emir of the city and a captain of Nur ad-Din's veterans assumed guardianship over him. The emir prepared to unseat all of his rivals in Syria and al-Jazira. In this emergency the emir of Damascus appealed to Saif al-Din of Mosul, a cousin of Gumushtigin, for aid against Aleppo, but he refused, forcing the Syrians to request the help of Saladin, who complied. Saladin rode with 700 horsemen across the desert, passing through al-Kerak and reaching Bosra. According to Saladin he was joined by "emirs, soldiers and Bedouins - the emotions of their hearts to be seen on their faces." By November 23 he arrived at Damascus in general acclamations and rested at his father's old home until the gates to the Citadel of Damascus were opened to him four days later. He installed himself in the castle and received the homage of the citizens.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Leaving his brother, Tughtigin as governor of Damascus, Saladin began to reduce cities that once belonged to Nur ad-Din, but were essentially independent. He claimed Hamah with ease, but avoided Homs due to the strength of its citadel. He moved north to Aleppo and besieging it on December 30, 1174, after Gumushtigin refused to abdicate his throne. Fearing capture by Saladin, as-Salih left his palace and appealed to the citizens not to surrender himself or the city to Saladin. Gumushtigin requested from Rashid ad-Din Sinan, the grand-master of the Assassins of Syria to assassinate Saladin in his camp. Sinan was happy to comply being at odds with Saladin himself by replacing the Fatimid control of Egypt. On May 11, 1175 a group of Assassins gained admission into Saladin's camp, but were immediately detected by Nasih al-Din Khumartekin of Abu Qubays; one was killed by one of Saladin's generals and the rest were cut down whilst escaping. To stop Saladin's progress Raymond of Tripoli gathered his own force by Nahr al-Kabir where they were well-placed for an attack. Saladin later moved to strike Homs instead but retreated after hearing news of a relief force being sent there by Saif al-Din.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Meanwhile, Saladin's rivals in Syria and al-Jazira spread propaganda against him, claiming he "forgotten his own condition" as servant of Nur ad-Din and showed no gratitude for he by attacking his son, rising "in rebellion against his Lord." Saladin countered this by ending the siege, claiming he was defending Islam from the Crusaders. His army returned to Hama and engaged the Europeans there, the Crusaders withdrew beforehand and Saladin claimed it "a victory opening the gates of men's hearts." Soon after though he returned to Homs and captured its citadel in March 1175, defeating the stubborn defense. The success alarmed Saif al-Din; as head of the Zengids he regarded Syria and Mesopotamia as his family estate and was enraged when Saladin attempted to usurp his dynasty's holdings. Saif al-Din mustered a massive army and sent to Aleppo, whose garrison were awaiting them. The combined forces of Mosul and Aleppo marched out to engage Saladin in Hama. Heavily outnumbered, Saladin originally sought to make terms with the Zengids by abandoning all conquests north of the Damascus province, but they refused, insisting he return to Egypt. Seeing no peaceful solution, Saladin prepared for battle in taking up a superior position on the hills. On April 13, 1175 the Zengid army marched to attack, but soon found themselves surrounded by the Ayyubid veterans; the battle was a crushing defeat for the Zengids and a decisive victory for Saladin, who pursued the fugitives to the gates of Aleppo. This forced as-Salih's advisers to recognize Saladin's control of the provinces of Damascus, Homs and Hama, and a number of towns outside Aleppo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After this victory Saladin proclaimed himself king and suppressed the name of as-Salih in the Friday prayers and Islamic coinage. From then on he ordered the prayers in the mosques of Syria and Egypt as the sovereign king and he issued at the Cairo mint gold coins bearing his official title; al-Malik an-Nasir Yusuf Ayyub, ala ghaya - "the King Strong to Aid, Joseph son of Job; exalted be the standard." The Abbasid caliph in Baghdad graciously welcomed Saladin's assumption to power and declared him "Sultan of Egypt and Syria." The battle of Hama did not end the battle for power between the Ayyubids and the Zengids, with the final conflict taking place in the spring of 1176. Saladin gathered vast reinforcement from Egypt while Saif al-Din was levying troops among the minor state of Diyarbakir and al-Jazira. When Saladin crossed the Orontes the sun was eclipsed, this was viewed as an omen and he continued north. He reached the site of the Sultan's Mound near Aleppo, where his troops encountered Saif al-Din's army. The battle ensued with the Zengids breaking Saladin's left wing and Saladin charged at the Zengid guard. The Zengids panicked and most of the guard were either killed or captured, Saif al-Din himself narrowly escaping. The entire Zengid camp and baggage was seized by the Ayyubids and the prisoners of war were given gifts and freed. The booty from the victory was distributed to the army, Saladin kept nothing to himself. Saladin pressed on to Aleppo, capturing Buza'a and Manbij in the process, but was still halted at the gates. He turned west to attack the fortress of A'zaz on May 15, 1176. Several days later, while resting in a captain's tent, an assassin attacked him and attempted to plunge a knife into his head. His head armor was not penetrated, thus Saladin managed to grab the assassin's hand and later killed. Unnerved, Saladin accused Gumushtigin and the Assassins of the plot and so increased his effort in the siege.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A'zaz capitulated on June 21, and Saladin then rushed his men to Aleppo to punish Gumushtigin. Again the efforts were resisted, but Saladin managed to secure not just a truce but rather a mutual alliance with Aleppo, where Gumushtigin and as-Salih were allowed to continue their hold on the city, in return they recognized Saladin as the sovereign over all of the territories he conquered. The emirs of Mardin and Keyfa, the allies of Aleppo, also recognized Saladin as King of Syria. When the treaty concluded the younger sister of as-Salih came to Saladin and requested the return of A'zaz; he complied and escorted her back to the gates of Aleppo with many gifts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Campaign Against the Assassins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_7">
			<Text>With the truces with the Zengids and the Kingdom of Jerusalem earlier - the summer of 1175 - Saladin now faced a new threat from the Ismaili sect known as the Assassins. Based in the an-Nusayriyah Mountains they held nine fortresses, all on high ground. As soon as he sent the bulk of his army to Egypt, Saladin led the remainder of his men into Assassin territory in August 1176; he later retreated the same month after laying waste to the countryside but failing to conquer any of the forts. Most Muslim historians claim that Saladin's uncle, the governor of Hama mediated a peace treaty between him and Rashid ad-Din Sinan. However, Sinan's panegyrist claims Saladin departed for fear for his own life at the hands of the Assassins. He supposedly had guards rig link lights and had chulk and cinders placed around his tent to detect the footsteps of the Assassins during a siege at Masyaf. According to this version of events, one night Saladin's guards saw a spark glowing down the hill before disappearing among the Ayyubid tents. Saladin then awoke from his sleep to find a figure leaving his tent. He found his lamps were displaced, beside his bed lay hot scones in the shape peculiar to the Assassins, and a note pinned by a poisoned dagger. The note threatened him that if he did not withdraw he would be killed. Saladin gave a loud cry and exclaimed that Sinan himself presented the note and left the tent.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Another claim suggests that Saladin hastily withdrew his army from Masyaf because they were urgently needed to repel a Crusader force near Mount Lebanon. Realizing he could not defeat the Assassins, Saladin sought to establish an alliance with them to rob the Europeans of a potent ally against him. Seeing the expulsion of the Crusaders as a mutual benefit and priority, Saladin and Sinan maintained cooperative relations afterward, Sinan sending contingents of his armies to bolster Saladin's men in a number of decisive subsequent battles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Rebuilding Egypt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_8">
			<Text>Leaving the mountains Saladin returned to Damascus and dismissed his Syrian soldiers to their homes and appointed Turan-Shah to govern Syria, as he and his Egyptian army made their way home, reaching Cairo by September 22, 1176. Absent for about two years, Saladin had a great deal to organize and supervise, namely fortifying and rebuilding the capital. Cairo's city walls were repaired and extended, Saladin commissioned the construction of the Cairo Citadel. The Bir Yusuf - "Joseph's Well" - was also built by Saladin; he chief construction at this time was the large bridge at Giza as a form of defense against potential Moorish invasion. Saladin commissioned the establishment of colleges such as the Madrasa of Sword Makers and ordering the internal administration of the country.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Palestine and Jerusalem</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_9">
			<Text>In November 1177 Saladin set out a raid of Palestine; the Crusaders recently forayed into the territory of Damascus, so Saladin saw the truce no longer held value to preserve. The Europeans sent a large section of their army to engage the fortress of Harim, leaving the south of Palestine with little garrison. Saladin saw that the perfect opportunity to attack, he marched to Ascalon, referring to it as the "Bride of Syria." William of Tyre claims the Ayyubid army was 26,000 strong, 8,000 of which from the elite forces. They raided the countryside, sacking Ramla and Lod and dispersing as far as the Gates of Jerusalem. The Ayyubids allowed King Baldwin IV of Jerusalem to enter Ascalon with his Templars without the precaution of an attack. While the Crusaders had only 375 knights there, Saladin hesitated to ambush them due to the presence of their highly skilled generals. On November 25, with the bulk of the Ayyubid army absent, Saladin and his garrison were themselves ambushed by the Europeans in the Battle of Montgisard. Before the garrison could think to form up, the Templar knight cut them down. Initially Saladin tried to organize the man into battle order, but as his guards were dying he concluded that defeat was inevitable. He and what remained of his men mounted camels and fled to Egypt.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Undeterred by the ambush, Saladin prepared for another battle with the Crusaders. In the spring of 1178 he was encamped under the walls of Homs and a few skirmishes happened between his generals and the Crusaders. Hama won a victory over the Europeans and brought the spoils and many prisoners of war to Saladin, he ordered the captives to be beheaded for "plundering and laying waste the lands of the Faithful." Saladin spent the rest of 1178 in Syria without so much as an exchange with his enemies. Reports came from Saladin's intelligence groups that the Crusaders were planning a raid in Syria. Thus he ordered one of his generals, Farrukh-Shah to guard the Damascus frontier with a thousand of his men to watch for an attack, retire and avoid the battle and light warning beacons on the hills for Saladin to march out. Led by King Baldwin, on April 1179 the Crusaders expected no resistance and waited to launch a surprise attack on Muslim herders east of the Golan Heights. Baldwin moved too boldly in pursuing Farrukh-Shah's men and was thus defeated by the Ayyubids. With the victory Saladin requested 1,500 horsemen from Egypt to reinforce the army[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In the summer of that year Baldwin set up an outpost on the road to Damascus in order to fortify a passage over the Jordan River called Jacob's Ford. Saladin offered 100,000 piece of gold for Baldwin to abandon the project, but he refused. Saladin then resolved to destroy it; as the Crusaders hurried to attack the Muslims they fell into disorder as the infantry fell behind. Despite early success the Europeans pushed the Muslims far enough for their lines to scatter and Saladin seize the advantage by rallying the troops to charge back to the Crusaders. The battle ended with a decisive Ayyubid victory and many high-ranking knights was taken; Saladin then besieged the fortress and it fell on August 30, 1179. In the spring of the following year, as Saladin was in Safad, anxious to again engage Jerusalem in a vigorous campaign, Baldwin sent messengers to him with proposals of peace. Due to drought and bad harvests Saladin agreed to a truce. Raymond of Tripoli denounced the truce but was eventually compelled to accept it after an Ayyubid raid in his territory in May.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_10">
			<Text>Current Affairs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_10">
			<Text>On June 1180 Saladin hosted a reception for Nur al-Din Muhammad, the Artuqid emir of Keyfa, in Geuk Su. There Saladin handed him and his brother Abu Bakr gifts to the value of over 100,000 dinars according to Imad al-Din. This was to cement an alliance with the Artuqids and impress other emirs in Mesopotamia and Anatolia. Originally Saladin offered to mediate relations between Nur al-Din and the Seljuk sultan Kilij Arslan II of Rum after the two fell into conflict. The sultan demanded Nur al-Din to return the lands given to him as a dowry for marrying his daughter when he discovered she was being abused and used as a way to gain Seljuk land. Nur al-Din requested Saladin to mediate but Arslan refused. When Saladin met the emir at Geuk Su, the top Seljuk emir, Ikhtiyar al-Din al-Hasan confirmed the sultan's submission, where an agreement was drawn up. Later Saladin was furious when he heard a message from Arslan accusing the emir of more abuses against his daughter. In response, Saladin threatened to attack Malatya, saying "it is two days march for me and I shall not dismount until I am in the city." Alarmed, the Seljuks pushed for negotiations; Saladin felt it was reasonable for Arslan to care for his daughter, but Nur al-Din took refuge with him and thus could not betray his trust. An agreement was eventually reached; Arslan's daughter would be sent away for a year, if Nur al-Din did not comply Saladin would drop his support for him.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Leaving Farrukh-Shah in charge of Syria, Saladin returned to Cairo at the start of the following year, it was alleged he intended to spend Ramadan in Egypt and then make the hajj pilgrimage to Mecca in the summer, yet for some reason he changed his mind over the pilgrimage and was seen surveying the Nile banks in June. Saladin was again engaged with the Bedouin, removing two-thirds of their fiefs as compensation for the fief-holders in Fayyum. The Bedouin were also accused of trading with the Crusaders, their grain was confiscated as punishment and were forced to migrate west. Later Ayyubid warships were plundered by Bedouin river pirates who were assaulting the shores of Lake Tanis. In the summer of 1181 Saladin's former palace administrator, Qara-Qush led a force to arrest Majd al-Din, a former deputy of Turan-Shah in the Yemeni town of Zabid, as he was entertaining Imad ad-Din al-Isafahani at his estate in Cairo. Majd al-Din was accused of misappropriating the revenues of Zabid, but Saladin believed there was no evidence to back up the claim. He had Majd al-Din released in return for a payment of 80,000 dinars, other sums were also paid to Saladin's brothers, al-Adil and Taj al-Muluk Buri. The detainment of Majd al-Din was part of a bigger discontent from the aftermath of Turan-Shah's departure from Yemen. While his deputies continued to send revenues from the province, centralized government was lacking and this caused internal arguments between Izz al-Din Uthman of Aden and Hittan of Zabid.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_11">
			<Text>Imperial Expansion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_11">
			<Text>On May 11, 1182 Saladin, half of the Ayyubid army and a number of non-combatants left Cairo for Syria. On the night before Saladin sat with his companions, the tutor of one of his sons quoted a line of poetry; "enjoy the scent of the ox-eye plant of Najd, for after this evening it will come no more." Saladin saw that as an evil omen, and he would ultimately never see Egypt again. Between then and his death Saladin would stretch the borders of the Ayyubid state to its very height; Saladin ravaged the countryside of Montreal castle, arriving in Damascus he sent Farrukh-Shah to attack Kawkab al-Hawa, in August the Ayyubids launched a joint naval and land assault to capture Beirut, Saladin ended the truce with the Zengids by besieging Aleppo for three days. When reaching Bira he was joined by Kukbary, the emir of Harran, and Nur al-Din of Hisn Kayfa. The combined forces took the cities of al-Jazira, one by one; Edessa, Saruj, ar-Raqqah, Karkesiya and Nusaybin, they all fell into Ayyubid control. Upon gaining the victory of Nusaybin word reached Saladin of Crusader raids in Damascus, he replied "Let them...whilst they knock down villages, we are taking cities; we will come back, we shall have all the more strength to fight them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His greatest acquisition was Aleppo; as he continued to Aleppo towns simply surrendered to him, the governor of Tell Khalid forfeit his town upon the mere vision of Saladin approaching the battlefield and Ain Tab ceded to the Ayyubids simply when the army moved to its direction. On May 21, 1182 Saladin arrived and camped outside Aleppo. Zangi offered no long resistance, he was unpopular with his subjects and in fact wanted to return to Sinjar, his previous residence. Zangi arranged an exchange where he would give Saladin Aleppo in exchange for the restoration of control of Sinjar, Nusaynib and ar-Raqqah, to hold these as Saladin's vassals. On June 12 Aleppo was formally under Ayyubid control, completely unknown to the citizen, they were taken by surprise when finding Saladin's standard over the citadel. Despite being short on cash, Saladin allowed Zangi to take all the stores of the citadel he could carry and to sell the rest. The capture of the city marked the end of more than eight years waiting since Saladin told Farrukh-Shah "we have only to do the milking and Aleppo will be ours." He also described the city as "the key to the lands" and "the city is the eye of Syria and the citadel is its pupil."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mosul was much more difficult to claim; Saladin faced the problem of taking a large city and justifying the conquest. Arriving on November 10, 1182 Izz al-Din would not accept Saladin's terms because he saw them as false and extensive, prompting Saladin to lay siege to the city. Despite many brief skirmishes and a declared stalemate by the caliph an-Nasir, Saladin sought to find a way out of the siege without disturbing his reputation and keep some military pressure. He concluded to attack Sinjar, after just fifteen days the city fell on December 30. The commanders broke discipline and plundered the city with the soldiers. On March 2, 1183 al-Adil from Egypt wrote to Saladin that the Crusaders had struck the "heart of Islam". Raynald de Châtillon sent a navy to raid towns along the coast of the Red Sea. The harassment wasn't designed to extend European influence or to take trade routes, but to simply engage in piracy. Nevertheless Imad al-DIn wrote that the raid alarmed Muslims due to their inexperience with neither attacks from the Red Sea nor the Crusaders. Al-Adil moved his ships to intercept the raiders under the command of Lu'lu, an Armenian mercenary, breaking the Crusader blockade, destroying most of the ships and chased after the survivors who anchored and fled into the desert. Saladin saw that the war against Mosul was going well, but he still failed to achieve his objectives, it wasn't until 1186 in a different siege did Mosul eventually fall into his control.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_12">
			<Text>Fighting the Crusaders</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_12">
			<Text>During all this campaigning, Saladin kept up appearances with the Crusaders. After reaching and sacking the empty town of Beisan, on September 30, 1182 Saladin's forces moved west to intercept Crusader reinforcements from Karak and Shaubak along the Nablus road, taking many prisoners. Saladin also harassed forces under the command of Guy of Lusignan, the Europeans were moving to al-Fula when Saladin sent 500 skirmishers to attack, while Saladin himself moved to Ain Jalut. As a further response to Raynald de Châtillon's raiding of the Red Sea, he twice attacked Raynald's fortress in Oultrejordan in 1183 and 1184. One of the Crusaders major military disasters was the Battle of Hattin; on July 4, 1187 the combined forces of Guy of Lusignan, King Consort of Jerusalem and Raymond III of Tripoli fell entirely to the Ayyubid army. The success there was a major turning point to the Crusades and would eventually earn Saladin much of the Kingdom of Jerusalem.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By this stage almost every Crusader city was taken by Saladin. Jerusalem itself capitulated on October 2, 1187 when, as the siege began, Saladin eventually promised terms of quarter to the Franks in the city. Saladin was originally unwilling to promise such quarters until Balian of Ibelin threatened to kill every Muslim and destroy Islamic shrines in Jerusalem if not provided. The agreement was reached and read out in the streets of the city so everyone could provide tribute to Saladin for their freedom in forty days; at the time the tribute was low, today the tribute would only be roughly $US50. Every Frank man, woman and child had to pay the levy, those that could not afford the tribute were ultimately set free by Saladin in any case, against the advice of his treasurers. Patriarch Heraclius of Jerusalem organised and contributed to a collection paying the tribute of 18,000 of the poorer citizens, leaving 15,000 to be enslaved. Upon the capture of Jerusalem Saladin summoned the Jews and permitted them to resettle in the city.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The capture of Jerusalem also triggered the Third Crusade, financed by England under a "Saladin tithe". Richard I of England led Guy of Lusignan's siege of Acre, conquering the city and executed 3000 Muslim prisoners, including women and children. Saladin responded in kind by killing every Frank captured between 28 August and 10 September. Saladin's armies fought in the Battle of Arsuf against Richard on September 7, 1191, to which the Ayyubids lost. Richard pressed on to Ascalon; Saladin, predicting his next move, emptied the city and camped a few miles away. As Richard arrived he was surprised to find the city in its state. The next day, as Richard prepared for departure, Saladin ambushed the Crusaders in a furious battle. Richard managed to rescue some of his men to retreat. After then every European attempt to reclaim Jerusalem failed. Richard had far too few men to sustain an attack on the city; 2000 men and 50 knights.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Saladin and Richard maintained an intriguing relationship and rivals; when Richard lost his horse at Arsaf, Saladin gave him two. Richard proposed his sister, Joan of England, Queen of Sicily, to marry Saladin's brother and Jerusalem would be their wedding gift. The two men never met, they communicated via written letter or messenger. They did agree to the Treaty or Ramla in 1192, where Jerusalem would still be Muslim but open to Christian pilgrimages. The treaty reduces the kingdom to a strip of coast from Tyre to Jaffa.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_13">
			<Text>Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_13">
			<Text>Shortly after Richard's departure from Damascus Saladin died of a fever on March 4, 1193. Saladin's purse at the time was a piece of gold and 40 pieces of silver, having given his wealth to his poorer subjects. Saladin was buried in a mausoleum in the garden of the Umayyad Mosque in Damascus. Centuries later Emperor Wilhelm II of Germany donated a marble sarcophagus to the mausoleum. The sarcophagus was not replaced, the mausoleum displays both sarcophagi to the viewing public.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_HEADING_14">
			<Text>Verdict of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_TEXT_14">
			<Text>The sheer size of this entry is a testament to the life of Saladin. In the Muslim world Saladin is a hero against the struggle against the Western world. Iraq has named a university, a suburb and a governorate after him. In the Western world Saladin earned a great reputation as a chivalrous knight, so much so that a poem was written of his exploits in the fourteenth century. While he faded out of history after the Middle Ages, he returned in a sympathetic light in Gotthold Ephraim Lessing's play "Nathan the Wise" in 1779, and in Sir Walter Scott's novel "the Tailsman" in 1825. Emperor Wilhelm II of Germany best describes Saladin in the inscription on his donated marble sarcophagus; "A Knight without fear or blame who often had to teach his opponents the right way to practice chivalry."</Text>
		</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_FIRST_GREETING_1">
			<Text>As-salamu alaykum, wanderer. I am Selahedînê Eyûb, Sultan of Egypt and Syria. God shines down and blesses upon me this empire you see before you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_FIRST_GREETING_2">
			<Text>Assalamu alaikum wa rahmatullah, good ruler. I am Selahedînê Eyûb, Sultan of Egypt and Syria. If we are ultimately fated to be enemies, then let us be friends for now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You have emerged the victor, congratulations. It was well fought, and I am pleased to have found a worthy adversary.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MC_SALADIN_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>We shall meet again, but until that day enjoy your victory. Treat my empire well, and I shall have no ill-wishes upon you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DOM Text-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_MC_AYYUBIDS_TEXT">
			<Text>Peace and blessings be upon you, oh great Saladin! From humble beginnings in a Kurdish family, your upbringing in Damascus saw you excel in all which you took part in. It was under your leadership that combined Arabic armies defeated the vile Crusaders of Europe in a series of victories in which you overcame overwhelming odds in order to prevail. None could stand against you, and your forces became pivotal in driving the Christians out of the Holy Land once more. From your stronghold of Cairo, you established the Ayyubid dynasty, one which would come to rule vast swathes of land, from Tunisia in the west to Mesopotamia in the East and Nubia in the South. Despite your overwhelming military power, you remained chivalrous, for which even your most fervent of enemies respected you. The Ayyubid dynasty lasted long after your death, defeating all those who wished to take her land for centuries before finally succumbing to threats from within. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh great Saladin, your people look to you to rebuild the might of the Ayyubid dynasty. Can you once again strike fear into the hearts and minds of your enemies with but a whisper of your name? Can you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>	
</GameData>