<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/13/2014 2:17:25 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_DESC">
			<Text>The Iberians</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>The Iberians</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Iberian</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_DOM">
			<Text>Hail Indibilis, king of the Ilergetes and powerful chieftain of Iberia. Together with your brother Mandonius you lead your people against Carthaginians and Romans, and any else who might try to tame the Iberian people. Although fierce and warlike with renowned mercenaries, the Iberians themselves were a reclused people, master sculptors and metal workers that peacefully traded their goods through the mediterranean and europe, until faced with foreign invasion. The Iberians, however, refused to yield to foreign forces and their resistance was lenghty, ferocious and bloody.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mighty chieftain, after many years of war the Iberians are long vanquished, and your people assimilated by foreign powerhouses. They need now more than ever a powerful and bold leader to guide them to freedom. Will you rise up to their calls, and unite the Iberian tribes? Will you restore your lands and build an empire to stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The term Iberian, as used by the ancient authors, had two meanings. One, more general, referred to the whole of the population of the Iberian peninsula. The other, more restricted, with an ethnic sense, to the people living in the eastern and southern coasts of the Iberian peninsula, where by the 6th century BC they had absorbed cultural influences from Phoenicians and Greeks. This civilization covers the entirety of the peoples who inhabited the peninsula, such as the Ilergetes, the Lusitani, the Tartessian and many more.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Terrain and Climate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The majority of Iberia is dominated by high plateaus and mountain ranges, including the Sierra Nevada in the south and the Pyrenees to the west. Iberian's climate is incredibly diverse. The southern areas bordering the Mediterranean Sea enjoy a mild Mediterranean and semi-arid climate, the central plain is Continental in nature, and the northern areas vary between Oceanic and Mountainous temperatures.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Iberian Groups</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The Iberians were not a clearly defined culture, ethnic group or political entity. The name is instead a blanket term for a number of peoples belonging to a pre-Roman Iron Age culture inhabiting the eastern and southeastern Iberian peninsula and who have been historically identified as "Iberian". Although these peoples shared certain common features, they diverged widely in some respects.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Roman and Greek sources often diverge about the precise location of each Iberian people and also about the list of Iberian peoples. There are some doubts about the ethno-linguistic affiliation of some of the peoples generally defined as Iberians, which included the Airenosi, Andosini, Ausetani, Bastetani, Bergistani, Castellani, Cessetani, Ceretani, Contestani, Edetani, Elisyces, Iacetani, Ilercavones, Ilergetes, Indigetes, Lacetani, Laietani, Oretani, Sedetani, Sordones, Suessetani, Turdetani and Vescetani or Oscenses. An unknown named tribe or tribes in the Balearic Islands (formed by the Pityusic Islands and Gymnesian islands) may have been iberian also.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Social Organization</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The Iberians lived in isolated communities based on a tribal organization. They also had a knowledge of metalworking, including bronze, and agricultural techniques. In the centuries preceding Carthaginian and Roman conquest, Iberian settlements grew in social complexity, exhibiting evidence of social stratification and urbanization. This process was probably aided by trading contacts with the Phoenicians, Greeks, and Carthaginians. Among the most important goods traded by the Iberians were precious metals, tin and copper. The Iberians traded extensively with other Mediterranean cultures. Iberian pottery has been found in France, Italy, and North Africa. The Iberians also had extensive contact with Greek colonists. The Iberians may have adopted some of the Greeks' artistic techniques.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Tartessos</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Tartessos was a harbor city and surrounding culture on the south coast of the Iberian Peninsula (in modern Andalusia, Spain), at the mouth of the Guadalquivir River. The Tartessians were rich in metal. In the 4th century BC the historian Ephorus describes "a very prosperous market called Tartessos, with much tin carried by river, as well as gold and copper from Celtic lands". Trade in tin was very lucrative in the Bronze Age, since it is an essential component of true bronze and is comparatively rare. The people from Tartessos became important trading partners of the Phoenicians, whose presence in Iberia dates from the 8th century BC and who nearby built a harbor of their own, Gadir.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Foreign Influence</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_6">
			<Text>The seafaring Phoenicians, Greeks and Carthaginians successively settled along the Mediterranean coast and founded trading colonies there over a period of several centuries.  Phoenician merchants founded the trading colonies on the south, while greeks settled the northeast. The Greeks coined the name Iberia, after the river Iber (Ebro). In the 6th century BC, the Carthaginians arrived in the peninsula while struggling with the Greeks for control of the Western Mediterranean. The Iberians were placed under Carthaginian rule for a short time between the First and Second Punic Wars. They supplied troops to Hannibal's army. The Romans subsequently conquered the Iberian Peninsula and slowly supplanted the local culture with their own.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_TEXT_7">
			<Text>The Iberian peninsula had been known since pre-Roman times for the high quality of swords originating from this region, which related to their manufacture, design, and ergonomics. Models such as the Iberian Falcata (a short sword), or the Gladius Hispanensis (a Roman short sword), were used by the Carthaginian and Roman troops from the times of the Second Punic War (2nd and 3rd Centuries B.C.).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Toledo steel, known historically as unusually hard, is from Toledo, Spain, which has been a traditional sword-making, steel-working center since about 500 BC, and came to the attention of Rome when used by Hannibal in the Punic Wars. Soon, it became a standard source of weaponry for Roman legions.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_1">
			<Text>Ilerda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_2">
			<Text>Tartessos</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_3">
			<Text>Numantia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_4">
			<Text>Tarraco</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_5">
			<Text>Bevipo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_6">
			<Text>Kartuba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_7">
			<Text>Edeta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_8">
			<Text>Toledo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_9">
			<Text>Sagunto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_10">
			<Text>Rhusadhir</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_11">
			<Text>Carpia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_12">
			<Text>Termes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_13">
			<Text>Iplacea</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_14">
			<Text>Salduie</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_15">
			<Text>Bilbilis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_16">
			<Text>Veleia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_17">
			<Text>Caetaria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_18">
			<Text>Illiturgis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_19">
			<Text>Carteia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_20">
			<Text>Uxama Argaela</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_21">
			<Text>Llívia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_22">
			<Text>Iaca</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_23">
			<Text>Bolskan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_24">
			<Text>Cáparra</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_25">
			<Text>Carissa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_26">
			<Text>Lebrija</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_27">
			<Text>Hispalis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_28">
			<Text>Cádiz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_29">
			<Text>Osca</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_30">
			<Text>Ponferrada</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_THE_IBERIANS_31">
			<Text>Castulo</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_0">
			<Text>Audax</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_1">
			<Text>Ditalcus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_2">
			<Text>Minurus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_3">
			<Text>Mandonius</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_4">
			<Text>Andobales</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_5">
			<Text>Egeria</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_6">
			<Text>Gauson</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_7">
			<Text>Corocotta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_8">
			<Text>Lady of Elche</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_THE_IBERIANS_9">
			<Text>Busadines</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS">
			<Text>Indibilis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Indibilis was king (Chieftain) of the Ilergetes, an ancient Iberian (pre-Roman) people of the Iberian Peninsula, together with his brother Mandonius. Polybius speaks of the brothers as the most influential and powerful of the Spanish chieftains in that time period. Indibilis fought with and against carthaginians and romans, alternating between the two as the situation seemed fit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_HEADING_2">
			<Text>With Carthage</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Indibilis fought against the Romans and sided with the Carthaginians at the Battle of Cissa in 218 BC, when the Roman Gnaeus Cornelius Scipio Calvus fought them. Indibilis was defeated at this battle and became a prisoner, along with the Carthaginian general Hanno. In 217 BC, Indibilis had regained his freedom and, with his younger brother Mandonius, decided to harass neighboring Spanish tribes that were friendly to, and in alliance with, Rome. When Hasdrubal Barca, who was in northwestern Spain, heard of this, he came back to help out his Spanish allies south of the Ebro River. At this time, the tide of war took a turn because of unexpected intelligence received by the Romans from the Celtiberians. The Celtiberi were induced to collaborate with the Romans and invade New Carthage. On the way there, the combined armies took three fortified towns and fought two successful battles with Hasdrubal and Indibilis with Mandonius.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]This pretty well kept Indibilis and Mandonius and their remaining tribesmen out of the picture until 211 BC. At that time, they gathered 7,500 Suessetani and joined forces with Hasdrubal. Publius Cornelius Scipio, father to Scipio Africanus and younger brother of Calvus, decided to attack the Iberian chieftain brothers as they were moving across his line of retreat from his camp. Scipio didn't want to be trapped and surrounded by Carthaginians He marched at midnight to meet them and skirmished with them about daybreak. Scipio was speared with a lance and killed here at the Battle of Castulo, part of the Battle of the Upper Baetis. Gnaeus Cornelius Scipio Calvus, Scipio’s older brother, was killed at the Battle of Ilorca, the other part of the battle of the Upper Baetis, a few days later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_HEADING_3">
			<Text>With Rome</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Even though the chieftains were generally pro-Carthaginian, for which they were rewarded by being given back their tribal territories after the death of the two Scipios in 211 BC, they soon changed their minds after the conduct of the Carthaginian general Hasdrubal Gisco. He demanded much money from them on his own whim and for his own benefit. He also required that the wife of Mandonius and the daughters of Indibilis be held at New Carthage in pledge for their fathers' fidelity. The hostages were part of the booty when Scipio Africanus captured New Carthage in 209 BC. Africanus treated them with much dignity and returned them to their rightful places, which impressed the Spaniards. This added to Africanus's already excellent reputation of his personal character.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The two brothers soon abandoned the Carthaginians and sided with the Romans. In 209 BC, they concluded a treaty of alliance with the Romans with most of the tribal territories of Spain, since basically they were their overall leader chieftains. They then collaborated in a campaign against Hasdrubal Gisco which ended in a victory at the Battle of Baecula in 208 BC.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Betrayal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Because of the presence of the reputable Roman general Africanus, Indibilis and Mandonius with their influence over all the territories of Spain was in friendly association with the Romans. However, on the rumor of the serious illness of Africanus and his possible death in 206 BC, they started a rebellion for the Romans to leave Spain. This rumor also started a mutiny at the military camp at the Sucro River, which involved some 8,000 soldiers.Indibilis and Mandonius sided with them, but Africanus became better and returned to good health and ultimately squelched the mutiny with the 35 main instigator ringleaders beheaded. He then went after the armies of Indibilis and Mandonius and slaughtered their army. Indibilis surrendered to Africanus asking for mercy. Indibilis and Mandonius were released to their territories with favorable terms. However, this special kindness on the part of Africanus did not have the effect he was hoping for. The next year, Africanus left Spain in the hands of his generals L. Lentulus and L. Manlius and returned to Rome to prepare for an attack on Carthage. Since Africanus was now gone, the only general Indibilis and Mandonius were deathly afraid of, they aroused the Spanish tribes and assembled an army of 30,000 foot soldiers and 4,000 cavalry and decided to rebel again. They soon realized their mistake, and in a battle with the Romans, the Spaniards were all but totally destroyed. Indibilis was killed in this battle and Mandonius escaped with the remnants of the army. He was soon given up by his own tribesmen and then killed by the Roman generals.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Judgment of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_TEXT_5">
			<Text>There is not enough information to determine Indibilis rule as a king, however it is known that he and his brother were the most influential and powerful of the Iberian chieftains of their time; for bad or for good.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_LIVED">
			<Text>c 258 - 205 BC</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_NAME">
			<Text>Indibilis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of the Iberians</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TCM_INDIBILIS_TITLES_1">
			<Text>King of the Ilergetes</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TCM_INDIBILIS_SHORT">
			<Text>Mediterranean Influence</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TCM_INDIBILIS">
			<Text>Gain + 1 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Artist point in the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital city for every incoming [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE] Trade Route of a different civilization. Gifted military units generate [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for you and return to your control if you are at war with their new owner.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TCM_CASTRO">
			<Text>Oppidum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENTTCM_CASTRO_TEXT">
			<Text>An oppidum is a large defended settlement associated with the Celtic late La Tène culture. In Iberia, they are usually referred to as Castro, fortified villages often built in naturally protected areas and full of circular constructions. In times of conflict, the people who lived in open field moved to these strategically located buildings to ensure their safety. The buildings could also have other purposes such as control of territory, vigilance of crops, etc. Its situation on the territory compared to other castros suggests that there was a definite strategy when choosing its location, allowing the communication by signals between them as a defensive network.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Oppidum can only be built on a Hill tile, and not adjacent to any other Oppidum. It increases the defensive [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength of units stationed in that tile by +25%. Additionally, any unit that pass through the tile will ignore terrain movement costs, be able to move after attacking and receive +33% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength when flanking for one turn.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_TCM_CASTRO">
			<Text>Build Oppidum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_TCM_CASTRO_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocked at the discovery of Masonry, may only be built on hill tiles and not adjacent to another Oppidum. The Oppidum generates +1 Culture and grants +25% defense to units on the same tile. Units that pass through a Oppidum ignore terrain costs, may move after attacking and gain +33% Flanking Combat Strength bonus for one turn.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_TCM_CASTRO_REC">
			<Text>Build a Oppidum, to generate extra culture and help defend your lands.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_IBERIAN_GUERRILA">
			<Text>Iberian Guerrila</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_IBERIAN_GUERRILA_HELP">
			<Text>Ignore terrain movement cost, may move after attacking and gain +33% Flanking [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength bonus until the next turn.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_IBERIAN_SOLDIER">
			<Text>Iberian Soldier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_IBERIAN_SOLDIER_HELP">
			<Text>If gifted, this unit generates culture to you and return to your control if you are at war with their new owner.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_TOLEDO_STEEL">
			<Text>Toledo Steel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_TOLEDO_STEEL_HELP">
			<Text>If gifted, this unit generates gold to you. +15% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_GIFTED_UNIT">
			<Text>Iberian Gifted Unit</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_GIFTED_UNIT_HELP">
			<Text>This unit was gifted by Iberia, but won't generate culture or gold for them or return to their control due to a event.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TCM_SCULPTOR_WORKSHOP">
			<Text>Sculptor Workshop</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TCM_SCULPTOR_WORKSHOP_HELP">
			<Text>Increase the gold from incoming trade routes by +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold to you and to the trade route owner for every improved [ICON_RES_STONE] Stones, [ICON_RES_MARBLE] Marble, [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron, [ICON_RES_SILVER] Silver or [ICON_RES_GOLD] Gold on this city. The city must have at least one of the aforementioned resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_TCM_SCULPTOR_WORKSHOP_TEXT">
			<Text>Ancient Iberians were famed by their sculptures, done to perfection - some were so similar to Greek works that they could have been directly imported from that region. Almost all extant works of Iberian sculpture visibly reflect Greek and Phoenician influences, and Assyrian and Egyptian influences from which those derived; yet they have their own unique character. Within this complex stylistic heritage, individual works can be placed within a spectrum of influences. Overall the degree of influence is correlated to the work's region of origin, and hence they are classified into groups on that basis. The Levantine Group, mostly made between the 5th century B.C. and the period of Roman domination that had deep greek and punic influences. The southern group is principally composed of sculptures found in sepulchers, and other funeral monuments, in the Andalusian region. Most of them display heavy Phoenician influence. The western group is composed of granite funeral stelae from Portugal and Galicia that represent foot soldiers dressed in tunics and armed with round shields. In the center of the Peninsula, between the rivers Douro and Tagus there are many granite sculptures roughly carved in the form of bulls, or perhaps some other animal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TCM_SCULPTOR_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Sculptor's Workshop is the Iberian Unique Building, replacing the Stone Works but that has a different overall focus, that instead of increasing the city production it increases its gold from incoming trade routes. The Sculptor's Workshop generates +1 Gold from incoming trade routes to you and to that trade route owner for every improved source of [ICON_RES_STONE] Stones, [ICON_RES_MARBLE] Marble, [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron, [ICON_RES_SILVER] Silver or [ICON_RES_GOLD] Gold in the city, and it must have one of the aforementioned resources.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_GIFTED_UNIT_NOTIFICATION_TITLE">
			<Text>Iberian Mercenaries Hired!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_GIFTED_UNIT_NOTIFICATION">
			<Text>The Iberians have gifted us some units. They will, however, return to their control if we attack them.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Indibilis, and together with my brother Mandonius I rule the Ilergetes. You are much welcomed into our lands; as long as you don't intend to stay.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Hail there, fellow chieftain. I am Indibilis, king of these lands full of riches. I hope we may be friends, as long as you do not interfere with my people; we value freedom above all.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You are a worthy leader; in another life, maybe, I would have followed you. But now, I ask you to take good care of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>I see you have lots of time, but by the gods stop wasting mine!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_REPEAT_TRADE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>I don't care if you are a king, emperor or whatever, if you don't shut up right now I'll throw you off the hill.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>You truly are brave to show your face here! Tell me what do you want then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>In what I and my people may be of use to you, my friend?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>Aren't you at war with someone? Oh yes, I remember now, one of my dearest friends is fighting alongside your enemies! He said killing your men felt like a massacre, you know, because of how defenceless they were.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>Come in friend, you must be in hurry as I heard you were at war. Maybe you could use some help from us?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Welcome, fellow warlord, I've heard many tales of your conquests. I must advise you against continuing them, though.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you purchased so many lands around me; makes it easier to raid them. What do you want here?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING">
			<Text>I understand your desire for expansion and greatness, but please do so elsewhere, as these lands belong to my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>I see your people all around my lands now. I hope you realize that someday I'll get tired of it...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>I see you have the heart of a conqueror, my friend, but I'd take a small break from it. The other chieftains are getting uneasy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Your military is well known around these parts. Do you happen to use our steel in your weapons?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>I have heard your lands are quite rich, like ours. Let us celebrate that!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES_1">
			<Text>It troubles me that, if a civilization so irrelevant and weak as yours can remain independent, of what use are our armies?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY_1">
			<Text>With an army weak like that, I'm sure you are in need of some mercenaries. I can recommend some, if you want.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>I've heard your tales, brute warlord. What do you want in my lands?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human is asking the AI for something -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>These lands belong to the Iberian people! Maybe you are the one who should have settled elsewhere.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Very well, but don't abuse our friendship further...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Attacked by Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Now I finally agree with you! Let us end our differences in the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>This mistake was your last! Don't hide behind your troops now, I want to put a spear through your heart in the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>I truly did not wish to wage war against you, but so be it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>So this is what betrayal feels like? Very well then, it is time to end you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_INDIBILIS_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Peace? To our last breath, we will fight. Peace will only come when a spear pierces your heart, or mine.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>